>> Everyone to panel one
>> 大家请到第一讨论小组
on NDN application development.
在NDN应用开发上。
This was learned and next steps and these
这是学习到的内容，以及接下来的步骤。
moderated by Davide Pesavento.
由 Davide Pesavento 主持。
Davide is a researcher
Davide是一名研究员
at Nest and for many years
在Nest工作了许多年
has been one of the main NDN
已经成为主要的NDN之一
coordinates developers.
协调开发人员。
Davide, go ahead, please.
Davide，请继续。
>> Hello everyone. Welcome back.
>> 大家好。欢迎回来。
Welcome to the first panel of
欢迎参加第一个小组讨论会
the 2021 edition of
2021年版
the NDN Community meeting.
NDN社区会议。
My name is Davide Pesavento and today I have
我叫Davide Pesavento，今天我有
the pleasure and honor
的荣幸和荣誉
of moderating this panel.
的主持这个小组讨论。
The topic is application development.
主题是应用程序开发。
We will be looking at the lessons
我们将会研究从中学到的教训。
learned from
我们从中学到的
years of developing and
多年来的开发和
operating NDN applications.
经过多年的开发和运行NDN应用程序。特别是我们将会关注
Especially we'll be looking
特别是我们将会关注
at the next steps.
在接下来的步骤。
Where do we go from here?
我们接下来去哪里？
We have six panelists with us.
我们有六位小组成员在场。
You can go ahead and turn on
您可以继续打开
your cameras in the meantime.
您可以继续打开您的相机。
I will introduce them shortly.
我将很快介绍他们。
But before I do that, I'd like to very
但在我这么做之前，我想要非常
briefly explain the reasons
简要解释原因
and goals of this panel.
以及这个小组的目标。
I'll keep it short,
我会尽量简短。
I want to maximize the time
我想最大化利用时间。
for actual discussion.
为了实际讨论。
[NOISE]
~!@#$%^&*()
Why are we doing this?
我们为什么要这么做？
Well, on the end research
嗯，在研究的最后阶段
has been ongoing now
现在已经持续进行了
for over a decade and during this time,
已经超过十年了，在此期间，
many applications have been built using NDN.
已经有许多应用程序是使用NDN构建的。
More recently as we've
最近，我们已经
heard from [inaudible] first presentation,
听到了[听不清]的第一场演讲，
the very first presentation today,
今天的第一场演讲，
NDN research has transitioned
NDN研究已经过渡
to applications-driven research direction.
研究方向已经过渡到以应用为驱动。
We would think applications are important for
我们认为应用对于
the NDN development and
NDN开发和
evolution and research as a whole.
整体的演变和研究。
The experience and as a matter of fact,
我们获得的经验，实际上，
the experience that we gained,
我们获得的经验，
the lessons that we learned
我们学到的教训，
through this process,
通过这个过程，
has been invaluable for
已经非常宝贵了，对于
the evolution of NDN,
the evolution of NDN 已经非常宝贵了，对于 to refine the architecture,
to refine the architecture,
为了完善架构，
its core protocols.
再次强调，应用程序将扮演重要角色。
Again, applications will play
an extremely important critical role.
a very important critical role
在未来的NDN中发挥着至关重要的关键作用。
in the future of NDN.
在未来的NDN中。
However unfortunately,
然而不幸的是，
developing an NDN application
开发一个NDN应用程序
is still challenging today.
仍然具有挑战性。
It's difficult, requires a major effort
它很难，需要付出巨大的努力。
in developmentthe itself [NOISE].
It's hard and requires a lot of effort. You need them to be an expert.
You need them to be an expert
你需要他们成为专家。
in many and a lot of low-level details of
在许多低层次的细节上
NDN in order to build
NDN为了构建
an effective application that is not
一个有效的应用程序不是
a toy application operation
一个玩具应用程序操作
that does something useful.
它能够做一些有用的事情。
There's a desire of moving away from
有一种想要远离~!@#$%^&*()
this low-level individual handling
这种低级别的个体处理
of interest in data packets.
对数据包中的感兴趣内容。
The wire level of towards higher level APIs,
面向更高级别API的线级。
easy to use libraries.
易于使用的库。
Essentially, these panel came with
本质上，这些面板带有
a wish of making NDN more usable,
愿景是让NDN更加易用，
improve the developer experience.
提升开发者体验。
Improve APIs improved libraries,
提升API，改进库，
provide better tools,
提供更好的工具，
whether for developmental,
无论是为了开发，
for debugging of the network.
用于网络的调试。
What's going on in the network,
发生了什么事情在网络上，
why the application is not working,
应用程序为什么不工作，
why is it behaving like it does.
为什么它的行为会是这样的。
Is the deployment and bootstrapping can
部署和引导过程可能会
be time-consuming, clunky?.
耗时而笨拙。
But I'm going to stop here
但我就说到这里。
another panelist, I don't know.
另一位嘉宾，我不清楚。
I'll do the panelists do the complaining.
我会让小组成员来抱怨。
I'm told the simple wishes
我被告知了简单的愿望
to make NDN more useable.
为了让NDN更加实用。
Of course that's easier said than
当然，说起来容易
done and that's why this panel.
完成了，这就是为什么有这个面板。
We want to walk
我们想要走路
away from this panel with a list of
离开这个面板时带着一份清单
concrete practical items and suggestions that
具体实用的项目和建议，我们作为一个社区可以
we can take as a community we can
采纳并取得进步。
on over the next year or so.
在接下来的一年左右时间里。
Hopefully in a year from now,
希望在接下来的一年左右时间里，
the next community meeting we can report
在下一次社区会议上我们可以报告
back on what we accomplished.
在下一次社区会议上我们可以报告回顾我们所取得的成就。
I'm not expecting that we do
我们不应该期待我们做
everything we'll say today,
我们今天所说的一切，
even if we do just 10 percent of
即使我们只做到了百分之十
what we would say today,
我们今天所说的，
that's already, I think, a big achievement.
这已经是一个很大的成就了，我认为。
We have a little over an hour and
我们有一点多小时和
I prefer spending as much time as
我们有一点多小时和尽可能多的时间讨论~!@#$%^&*()
possible discussing
尽可能地讨论
rather than presenting slides,
而是进行口头陈述，
so I've asked our panelists to limit
所以我已经要求我们的小组成员限制
their initial remarks to
他们的初始发言限制在
about five minutes not
大约五分钟左右。
more than five minutes each.
每个超过五分钟。
If it's less than that, that's even better.
如果少于这个时间，那就更好了。
As already said, two
如前所述，两个
main directions, two main questions.
主要方向，两个主要问题。
What are the major pin points?
主要痛点是什么？
Focus even more on the second,
更加专注于第二个，
which is how we can improve
这是我们可以如何改进
the application developer experience.
应用程序开发者体验。
[NOISE] Without further ado
[噪音] 不用多说
, we're going to go,
我们将要去，
in that list shown here,
在这里显示的那个列表中，
this order, let me
在这个顺序中，让我
introduce our first panelist,
介绍我们的第一位小组成员，
Kathleen, and you can go
介绍我们的第一位小组成员，Kathleen，你可以开始分享了。
ahead and start sharing
请开始分享吧。
your screen while I introduce you.
在我介绍你的时候，请分享你的屏幕。
[OVERLAPPING] Kathleen Nichols is
凯瑟琳·尼科尔斯是
a CTO of Pollere.
凯瑟琳·尼科尔斯是Pollere的首席技术官。
He received a PhD in electrical engineering
他获得了电气工程博士学位。
from UC Berkeley long time ago.
他很久以前从加州大学伯克利分校毕业。
Her words not mine.
她的话，不是我的。
Her current interests are in using NDN
她目前的兴趣在于使用NDN
to solve network problems,
解决网络问题，
which has led to the development of
这导致了开发
the open source data-centric toolkit or DCT.
开源的数据中心工具包或称为DCT。
Although she retains a soft spot
尽管她心中仍保留着一片柔软之地
for netbook measurements.
为了测量上网本的尺寸。
Kathleen, floor is yours.
凯瑟琳，轮到你发言了。
>> I think I'm not going to
我觉得我不会
bother with any slides.
不去费心准备任何幻灯片。
I'm just going to talk right now,
我现在就直接说吧，
but the slide [OVERLAPPING]
但是幻灯片[重叠]
can go into the record.
可以记录下来。
I think first really wanted to start is
我认为首先真正想要开始的是
to say a few personal things that
要说一些个人的事情，
my relationship with ICN and
我的关系与ICN以及
NDN starts out as
NDN起初是
I'm married to Van Jacobson,
我和Van Jacobson结了婚，
so mostly over the years I've had
所以这些年来我主要有过
this front row seat without actually being
所以这些年来我主要有过这个前排座位，但实际上并未参与进去
in the arena until the past few years,
直到过去几年，我才真正参与到这个领域。
with an exception of
除了...之外
briefly back around 2010,
大约在2010年左右，
I spent some time when it was more CCN.
我花了一些时间，那时候它更多的是CCN。
But and actually a very interesting thing
但实际上是一件非常有趣的事情
is that some of
但实际上是一件非常有趣的事情，是那些早期进入...
these early ideas that came into
这些早期涌现出来的想法
then 2006 talk actually came when.
那么2006年的讨论实际上是什么时候发生的。
in
在
the '90s and he gave a gist
九十年代，他大致讲了一下。
mixed talk and I didn't realize this,
杂乱的谈话中我没有意识到这一点，
but he was trying this out on me at
但他当时正在我身上尝试这个，在我们第一次晚餐约会中说，
''Well, in the Internet,
"嗯，在互联网中，"
we're trying to connect endpoints,
我们正在尝试连接终端，
but we really want
但我们真的很想
this idea of somebody
这个关于某人的想法
walking into the room and
走进房间并且~!@#$%^&*()
saying who has the
说谁拥有这
time,'' then being able to get
时间，那么能够得到
the answer from the person
人给出的答案
What I do want to say though
我想说的是
is that one issue that I
我想说的是，那是一个我遇到的第一个攀登进入
encountered first climbing into
我遇到的第一个攀登进入
this arena is that
这个竞技场就是~!@#$%^&*()
it does seem like there's a lot
确实看起来有很多
of two things.
的两种情况。
One is it seems like there's a lot
一种是似乎存在很多
of pushback if you wanted to
存在很多反对意见如果你想要
look at things differently or if you start
看待事物的角度不同或者如果你开始
getting new insights when
从不同的角度看待事物或者当你开始工作时，获得新的见解。
you start working with things.
当你开始处理事情时。
I feel like it's
我感觉它是
too early in the development of
发展初期的
this architecture for us to be
这种架构对我们来说是为了
developing an orthodoxy and
发展一种正统观念和
how we look at things.
我们如何看待事物。
I think we need to be open-minded
我认为我们需要保持开放的心态。
because the idea of going from
因为从一个地方到另一个地方的想法
endpoint-oriented networking
端点导向的网络连接
to this view of networking
对这种网络观点
that is more data-oriented is really
对这种更加注重数据的网络观点确实不同，我们得绞尽脑汁，
different and we have to stretch our brains,
不同，我们得绞尽脑汁，
and I think as Lisa often says,
我们得绞尽脑汁，正如丽莎经常说的，让百花齐放。
let a thousand flowers bloom.
让千花竞放。
Another issue I encountered,
我遇到了另一个问题。
which I think you've already alluded to in
我认为你之前已经提到过在
the beginning, is the codebase.
开头部分，是代码库。
There's finding out what I
需要找出我什么 ~!@#$%^&*()
needed and untangling things and then
需要并解开事情然后
trying to figure out what code was from
试图弄清楚代码是从哪里来的
abandoned graduate student project
废弃的研究生项目
versus what was core.
与核心内容相比。
That's very difficult to get oriented.
这非常难以定位。
Again,
这非常难以定位。记得我一开始说的，
remember what I said in the beginning,
记得我一开始说的，
I'm a person married to Van Jacobson
我是与Van Jacobson结婚的人。
and if it hadn't been for Van telling me,
如果不是Van告诉我的话，
''Just ignore that, just focus on this,
"只管忽略那个，专注于这个，"
'' I think I would have just
''我觉得我本可以只是
like given up and said,
像放弃了一样说道，
"This is a huge mess."
“这是一个巨大的混乱。”
I also felt like I had license from
我也觉得我有权利来自
Van to go ahead and try
敢于去尝试
new things because he would say,
新事物，因为他会说，
''I don't like that way of doing it
''我不喜欢那种做事方式
then try something different.''
那就尝试一些不同的方法。
Of course the other advantage I've had is
当然，我拥有的另一个优势是
the same thing has
发生在我们世界上的大多数人身上。
In March of 2020,
在2020年3月，
we went into the shutdown.
我们开始进入封锁状态。
I've spent the last 18 months,
我过去18个月里，
even though I think most of you know Van,
即使我认为你们大多数人都认识Van，
this isn't his day job anymore,
他现在不再以此为主业了。
but we've spent all of
但我们已经花费了所有的时间在
our dinner conversations, dog walks,
我们的晚餐谈话，遛狗，
weekend talking because there's
我们周末聊天，因为没有别的事情要做，
nothing else to do for
我们周末聊天，因为没有别的事情要做，在过去的18个月里，谈论这个。
the last 18 months, talking about this.
在过去的18个月里，谈论这个。
The part of that is
这部分是~!@#$%^&*()
that's been really exciting.
这真的很令人兴奋。
I think it's some of the things
我认为这是其中的一些事情
that Lisa talked about like
，就像丽莎谈到的那样
let's think about applications in the edge
让我们思考一下边缘计算的应用场景。
and let's think of new ways to do things.
让我们想出新的方法来做事情。
I think there's been
我认为已经有过
this process that's really exciting and I
这个过程真的很令人兴奋，而我
really feel we need a way
真的觉得我们需要一种方式
of introducing other people to that.
来向其他人介绍那个。
I don't have brilliant ideas,
我没有什么天才的想法，
but I have a couple of thoughts.
但我有一些想法。
My overall thought is that
我总体的想法是
the community needs to be welcoming to
社区需要对...表示欢迎
those with problems to solve and
那些有问题需要解决的人和
provide clear usage guideline.
提供清晰的使用指南。
My practical thought is we
我的实际想法是我们可以考虑建立一个网站，
could think about having a website that
可以考虑建立一个网站，
has a couple of different applications
有几种不同的应用途径。
and here's this type of
这里有这种类型的应用途径，可能是会议讲座的应用。
application that could be meeting lecture.
这可能是会议讲座的应用。
Go into it. How do you do it? How is it done?
进入其中。你如何做到的？怎么做到的？
Here's the application so
这就是应用程序，所以
somebody could pull down
有人可能会拉下来
that code and maybe make
那段代码并且也许会对其进行一些更改并使其适应他们自己。
some changes in it and adapt it to their own.
对其进行一些更改并使其适应他们自己。
Then some of the stuff I've been working
然后，我一直在工作的一些事情
on more publicly is IoT,
在更公开的领域是物联网，
and then I've also been
然后我也一直在
working with operand networks,
一直在与操作数网络合作，
but it's up to
但这取决于
them what they want this share.
但这取决于他们想要这份股份。
But you can have an IoT application,
但你可以拥有一个物联网应用程序，
somebody can pull it down and do it.
有人可以拉下来做这件事。
Then the other part of that is each of
那么其中的另一部分是每一个
these nice large friendly
这些好看的、大的、友好的
letter could have linked
信可能已经联系上了
to the researchers who are
可能已经联系上了的研究人员或他们的团队是
particularly interested in doing
特别感兴趣的是做
this or who put
把这个或者是谁放~!@#$%^&*()
this code out there so
将这段代码放出去，以便
that somebody could contact them.
有人可以联系他们。
It could be a way to get
这可能是一个获取
in industrial funding,
在工业资金方面，
but it could also be a way to
但这也可能是一种方式来
get new grad students.
吸引新研究生。
But the whole plan is it
但整个计划就是这样。
needs to be easy to use,
需要易于使用，
and if each piece was
如果每一件事物都是
focused around a particular type
围绕着一个特定类型的应用，
that might be a good thing.
这可能是一件好事。
But here I'm not going to do this,
但我在这里不打算这么做，
I'm just saying this would be
但我只是说这将会是
a nice thing to have.
一个好东西。
It's always easy to tell other people what to
总是很容易告诉别人应该怎么做。
do as opposed to actually doing that.
与实际去做相比，只是说说而已。
I've probably used up my time, but thanks.
我可能已经用完了我的时间，但还是谢谢。
>> Thank you, Kathleen.
>> 谢谢你，凯瑟琳。
Next up is Peter.
接下来是彼得。
Peter Gusev is a software engineer
彼得·古谢夫是一名软件工程师
and staff researcher at the UCLA REMAP.
和加州大学洛杉矶分校REMAP的研究人员及工作人员。
That's the Research and Engineering
那是研究与工程
in Media and Performance Lab.
在媒体与表演实验室。
His main activities include
他的主要活动包括
designing and prototyping a real time
设计和原型制作实时
interactive distributed systems for
交互式分布式系统用于
theatrical and live performances.
剧院和现场表演。
Using cutting edge technologies
使用尖端技术
for [NOISE] live sensing,
为了实时感应，
media processing, AR VR.
媒体处理，增强现实与虚拟现实。
Peter actively participates in
彼得积极参与
the development of NDN applications
NDN应用程序的开发
for real-time navigable media and
实时可导航媒体和
mixed realities such as NDN.
混合现实技术，例如NDN（命名数据网络）。
While doing so, he also contributes
在这个过程中，他也做出了贡献
to the open source NDN
向开源NDN社区贡献了力量
community per
~!@#$%^&*()
building NDN tools and libraries.
构建NDN工具和库。
One such example is
一个这样的例子是
the DND RTC library for video conferencing.
用于视频会议的DND RTC库。
His previous professional background
他以前的专业背景
is networking software,
是网络软件，
augmented reality,
增强现实，
mobile application development,
移动应用开发，
and video streaming software.
和视频流媒体软件。
Peter holds a Bachelors
彼得拥有学士学位
and Masters degrees in
和硕士学位专业是
Informatics and Computer Science from
Informatics and Computer Science from 和硕士学位专业是 информатика и вычислительная техника от
the Baumann Moscow State
Bauman Moscow State Technical University
Technical University,
工业大学，
as well as a Masters in
以及硕士学位专业是
Business Information Systems from
商业信息系统专业来自 Throswap University of Technology.
the Throswap University of Technology.
特罗斯瓦普理工大学。
Peter, go ahead.
彼得，开始吧。
>> Thanks, Davide. Sorry for the long text,
>> 谢谢，达维德。对不起，文本有点长，
I should have shortened it.
我应该把它缩短一些。
Do you see my slides?
你看到我的幻灯片了吗？
>> Yeah.
>> 是的。
>> Hopefully my presentation
>> 希望我的演讲
will be quick and short.
将会简短迅速。
I've been involved with NDN for
我一直参与着NDN工作，在不同的职能中度过了过去八年。
the past eight years in different capacity.
在不同的职能中度过了过去八年。
I haven't been actively participating for
我没有积极参与
the past two years and
过去的两年里
currently I'm back on a small project.
目前我又回到了一个小项目上。
I have some experience building NDN libraries
我有一些构建NDN库的经验。
and applications since 2013.
自2013年以来，我有一些构建NDN（命名数据网络）库和应用程序的经验。
I think the main pinpoint is
我认为主要的难点是
that NDN project likes manpower,
我认为主要的难点是那个NDN项目缺乏人手，
people who will dedicate
的人将致力于
their time to make NDN platform friendly.
他们将致力于使NDN平台用户友好。
It's a complicated issue
这是一个复杂的问题。
and I think we'll
我们将会在本次会议中讨论这个问题。
but I would like to focus now
但我现在想要集中讨论
on few things that are,
在少数几件确实如此的事情上，
I think from my position
我认为从我的立场来看
of application developer,
的应用程序开发者，
I would say spoiled application developer,
我会说被宠坏的应用程序开发者，
a few things that NDN should have today.
现代网络命名数据（NDN）应该具备的一些特性。
Today's spoiled
今天被宠坏了
application developers like me,
应用程序开发者像我这样的人，
they would like to go on a website and
他们希望能上一个网站并且
they would like to see a QuickStart guide.
他们希望能看到一个快速入门指南。
They heard something about
他们听说了一些关于~!@#$%^&*()
the technology and then they
他们听说了一些关于这项技术，然后他们想要立刻尝试一下。
want to try it out right away.
他们想要立刻尝试一下。
In the first 15 minutes,
在最初的15分钟里，
they want to play with
他们想要一起玩耍
it and then decide whether they
它，然后决定是否他们
want to go further
想要更进一步
to see what libraries are available,
想要查看有哪些库可用，
what use cases are
要查看有哪些用例可以被这项技术覆盖
covered by this technology
可以被这项技术覆盖
and maybe start building their own app.
可以开始构建他们自己的应用程序。
When I go on the main website of IPFS,
当我访问IPFS的主网站时，
I see huge letters about IPFS,
我看到了关于IPFS的巨大字母，
what it is, it's
它是什么，它就是
just four words and
它是什么，它就是，只有四个字，然后有两个按钮，
then there are two buttons,
然后有两个按钮，
get started and how it works.
开始使用和它的工作原理。
Pretty clear. Then you can go check
很清楚。那么你可以去查看一下。
the name data networking website and it's
名称数据网络网站及其
quite confusing to figure
相当难以弄清楚我应该从哪里开始。
out where do I start.
弄清楚我应该从哪里开始。
Even frequently asked questions,
即使是常见问题，
they don't have this question answer;
他们没有这个问题的答案；
where do I start?
我该从哪里开始？
Quick Start guide I think
快速入门指南我认为
is a must have for NDN.
是NDN必不可少的。
The other thing that I
The other thing that I think is confusing is the number of 我认为令人困惑的另一件事是数量的多少。
think is confusing is the number of
我认为令人困惑的是数量的多少。
different libraries that we
不同的图书馆我们~!@#$%^&*()
have for NDN and it's
have for NDN and it's ~!@#$%^&*()
not clear which ones to use.
不清楚该使用哪一个。
I think since I joined the project,
我认为自从我加入项目以来，
we had ADN CPP and then NDN CXX.
我们有ADN CPP，然后是NDN CXX。
When I was talking to other people about
当我和其他人谈论
the project I'm working on,
我正在做的项目，
second question was why
第二个问题是为什么
are you using NDN CPP,
你在使用NDN CPP吗？
what's the difference from NDN CXX,
NDN CXX与NDN CPP有什么区别？
and I was confused.
我感到困惑。
I was not aware of
我之前不知道
what are the difference, why am I using it?
有什么不同，我为什么要使用它？
I think there should be
我认为应该有
a single high-level library.
一个高级的单一库。
By high level, I mean a library
By high level, I mean a library 是指一个高级的库。
that is data-oriented,
这是面向数据的，
provides data-oriented API.
提供面向数据的API。
That means that I don't have to care
这意味着我不必在意
about interests and data packets,
关于兴趣和数据包，
all I have to care is
我唯一需要关心的是
about fetching my data from the network.
我唯一需要关心的是从网络上获取我的数据。The library hopefully will
The library hopefully will
图书馆希望能够
handle multiple segments,
处理多个部分，
it will handle verification
它将处理验证工作
if I provide the keys,
如果我提供了密钥，
it will manifest NDN principles
它将体现NDN原则
like data immutability,
像数据不可变性，
and it will not allow me to create
并且它不允许我创建
two different data objects
两个不同的数据对象
with the same name.
具有相同名称。
If it can help me to handle
如果它能帮助我处理
my certificates so I don't
处理我的证书，这样我就不用
have to worry about how should I
处理我的证书，这样我就不用担心我应该如何签字，如果我想部署
sign if I want to deploy
处理我的证书，这样我就不用担心我应该如何签字，如果我想部署。
n nodes in the local network,
本地网络中有n个节点，
how should I set up
如何设置
the hierarchical relations,
层级关系，
or should it be a web of trust?
还是应该是一个信任网络？
The library can help me to do
图书馆可以帮助我去做
that in some way.
那在某种程度上。
The other pin point during the year is was
那年的另一个重点是
setting up the NFD
建立NFD
and setting up the conductivity.
建立导电性。
NDN is always talking about data-centricity
NDN总是在谈论以数据为中心。
but once you start working with it,
但一旦你开始使用它，
you have to think about the hosts,
你必须考虑到主机，
how they connected, are
他们是如何连接的，是否连接了？
they connected or not?
他们连接了吗？
What are the routes? Are they correct or not?
这些路线是什么？它们正确吗？
Then you start checking
然后你开始检查
it 20 times a day because
一天之内重复它20次因为
packets don't arrive or
数据包未能到达或者
something is improperly configured.
某些设置配置不当。
Manual configuration is a big downside.
手动配置是一个很大的缺点。
As a demo examples,
作为演示示例，
let's put up some demo examples.
让我们展示一些演示示例。
Not the toy apps,
不是那些玩具应用程序，
but something closer to the reality and these
但是更接近现实的东西，这些
are just the two examples
只是两个例子
that I have in mind that I'm working with,
我脑海中想到的，我正在研究的，
so these are things like
所以这些就像是
multi-homing for
多宿主技术用于
your data, redundant storage.
您的数据，冗余存储。
This is something that NDN
这是NDN可以提供的东西，与IP相比具有明显的优势。
can provide clear benefit compared to IP.
可以提供与IP相比明显的好处。
Edge services like machine learning,
边缘服务比如机器学习，
processing of your life media,
处理您的生活媒体，
and then processing this data
并处理这些数据
produced by machine learning
由机器学习产生
nodes and we're moving it
节点，我们正在移动它
down to pipeline in
移动到管道中
your applicant distributed app.
您的申请人分布式应用程序。
Maybe one more slide on the example of
也许再加一张幻灯片来举例说明
API that I would like to
我想要的API
see in NDN libraries.
在NDN库中看到的。
The API that to me looks very
The API that to me looks very ~!@#$%^&*()
data-centric where I don't have
数据为中心的地方，我不需要
to worry about the interests.
担心利益问题。
I don't have to worry about
我不必担心
where assembly my object
组装我的物体在哪里
from the multiple data packets.
从多个数据包中。
I just react to
我只是对此作出反应
borrowing the terminology
借用术语
from reactive programming,
来自响应式编程，
I would like to react in
我想要做出反应，在
a synchronous manner to
同步的方式去
the objects arrive and prompt the network.
物体到达并促使网络响应。
I think that's it from my side.
我认为我这边已经结束了。
>> Thank you. Thanks, Peter.
>> 谢谢。谢谢，彼得。
Next talk, but I'd like to welcome
下一个环节，但我想欢迎
Marcin into this,
to the stage Marcin Spoczynski
to the stage Marcin Spoczynski
登上舞台的是Marcin Spoczynski
is a Senior Research in
是一位高级研究员在
Scientist at Inter Labs.
科学家在Inter实验室工作。
His research interests are in
他的研究兴趣在于~!@#$%^&*()
Edge and Cloud Network and Compute Design,
边缘和云网络与计算设计，
Offloading Cloud Applications,
卸载云应用程序，
Industrial Control,
工业控制，
Determinacy Networking in India.
印度的确定性网络。
He has more than 15 years of experience
他有超过15年的经验。
in Designing and Developing
在设计和开发
End-To-End Systems,
端到端系统，
Network Applications and Software
网络应用与软件
Architectures. Marcin, take it away.
架构。Marcin, 接下来由你来讲。
>> Let me share the screen,
>> 让我分享屏幕。
you guys have some problem.
你们似乎有些问题。
I don't know if you can see the slides.
我不知道你是否能看到幻灯片。
I think I have some problems with
我认为我有一些问题。
the full-screen mode. Can you see the slides?
全屏模式。你能看到幻灯片吗？
>> Yes.
>> 是的。
>> Okay. I don't
>> 好的。我不知道为什么但它不起作用。
know why but it doesn't work.
我不知道为什么但它不起作用。
I will start in the different ways.
我将以不同的方式开始。
I think where we are,
我认为我们所在的位置，
we are seeing a lot of the work
我们正在看到很多工作
and especially in the businesses
和尤其是在商业领域
to support the Edge systems.
支持边缘系统。
From my understanding,
根据我的理解，
and research that we did,
和我们所做的研究，
there is a lot of the opportunities for
有很多机会用于
NDN to be a part of this Azure evolution.
NDN 将成为这一 Azure 进化的一部分。
But the first thing that we want to see,
但我们首先想要看到的是，
especially, lots of those,
尤其是，许多这样的，
the Edge developers are going to
Edge开发者们将要
be the students or
成为学生或者
the people who just
成为学生或者刚刚~!@#$%^&*()
starting with the software career and so on.
开始软件行业生涯等等。
We would like to see actually in
实际上我们想要看到在
the comparative to other people
与其他人相比
[LAUGHTER] that's we're here before
[笑声] 我们之前就在这里
much more dispersed language support.
支持更多分散的语言。
For example, we know that we have this,
例如，我们知道我们有这个，
the goal and support at
我们的目标和支持在~!@#$%^&*()
the moment in the case of the NDN but we
在NDN案例中的那一刻，但我们想要看到那些
would like to see those
想要看到那些
cool languages like harass
酷炫的语言，例如harass
and so on can be supported with the NDN.
可以通过NDN得到支持。
I do believe there is less and
我确信那里需要的更少，即使在像
less needs even in the spaces like
那里需要的更少，即使在像这样的空间中。
in those gel for the languages like
在那些像胶体一样的语言中
C++ and C because lots of the push,
C++和C因为很多推动，
it's about the writing
它是关于写作的。
easily those piece of the Software.
这些软件的部分很容易。
I think this is the great
我认为这很棒
opportunity to wrap up
抓住机会总结一下
for any new software developer or even
对于任何新的软件开发者甚至
to ship it to the business,
将其交付给业务部门，
is to have those support
是为了让那些支持
those new Cloud-native Software and
那些新的云原生软件和
especially that's they bring
尤其是它们带来的
a lots of the support,
很多支持，
especially related to security and so on.
特别是与安全等方面有关。
Another point that I think is very
另一个我认为非常
important is to provide
重要的是提供
this bridge between
这座桥梁是连接
the business and research.
这座桥梁是连接商业和研究的。
That's a speciality because I seen them
这是一种特殊情况，因为我见过它们。
ask on the questions,
提出问题，
why the researchers will
为什么研究人员会
need to the brain via
需要对大脑进行
integration out limitation because
需要对大脑进行整合以消除局限性，因为这不是一项研究。
this is not a research.
这不是一项研究。
The problem is that business will never,
问题在于，商业永远不会，
in the most the cases one take a code,
在大多数情况下，一个人会取一个代码，
if they no one see it is the easy way
如果没人看到，这是一种简单的方式。
of approaching the Software.
接近软件的方式。
Without this integration, which
如果没有这种集成，哪个
means the great API and integration
意味着出色的API和集成
with all of those automation software
带有所有那些自动化软件
and most of those they will
和他们中的大多数将会
never catch even they see
永远也抓不到，即使他们看见了
the clear gains of it.
它们清晰的收益。
Together with that, as we are mostly in
结合这一点，因为我们主要是在~!@#$%^&*()
this Data-driven part and for Data-driven,
这个数据驱动的部分，对于数据驱动来说，
we need to have
我们需要有
those observability tools.. At this moment,
我们需要有 those observability tools.. At this moment, as I show, we must be using
as I show, we must be using
正如我所示，我们必须使用
those IP tools for observability.
我们必须使用那些IP工具来进行可观测性。
But what we would like to see,
但我们希望看到的是，
it's just native way to support
它只是一种本地化的支持方式
those together with time series database
这些与时间序列数据库一起使用
or to having the possibility
或者拥有可能性
to run the queries in NDN fashion?
以NDN方式运行查询？
Me, especially when you see the address space
我，特别是当你看到地址空间时
of those time-series databases.
那些时间序列数据库。
You will see a lots of things in
你会看到很多东西在
common with Windows NDN systems.
与Windows NDN系统有很多共同之处。
One of the next point,
下一个要点是，
it's a thinking how those,
它是一种思考，那些如何，
NFD components with software,
NFD组件与软件，
the things like time sensitive mess.
像对时间敏感的混乱事务。
Looking at the Edge and the lots of
看着边缘和许多
the Edge use cases and
边缘用例和
not exactly industrial,
并不完全是工业的，
we see the lots of the needs
我们看到了许多需求
are for the bounded latency.
是为了有界延迟。
But this bounded latency it should be somehow
但这种有界延迟应该以某种方式
exposed in this NFD work.
在这个NFD工作中暴露出来。
I think that's is the one of
我认为那是其中之一
the key research how actually to apply
关键研究如何实际应用
the idea like time boundaries
时限的概念
for chunk latencies or
对于块延迟或
for those system and how to expose
对于那些系统以及如何暴露
this even in with the API developers.
这甚至包括与API开发者的合作。
The last, which is the lots
这是最后的，也是最多的。
of the work which is required for Edge,
这是Edge所需工作的一部分，
is how we provide those hooks
这就是我们提供那些钩子的方式。
for multiple types and
为了适应多种类型和
especially that's we have
尤其是我们拥有
lots of heterogeneity exists,
存在许多异质性，
or from x86 through
或从 x86 通过
the different architectures that I supported.
我支持的不同架构。
I think there is a lots of needs,
我认为有很多需求，
but the thing is what I think it just
但问题是我只是认为它仅仅
shows that feasibility which
表明了那种可行性。
can easily translate to the business needs,
可以轻松转化为业务需求，
but that's require,
但这是必需的，
I do believe the lots of it,
我确实相信它的很多部分，
from library through
从图书馆穿过
integration and so forth.
集成等等。
But then of course,
但那当然，
it can easily ask
它可以轻松地询问
the businesses to support your work.
它可以轻松地询问企业来支持你的工作。Thank you.
Thank you.
谢谢。
>> Thanks a lot Marcin.
>> 非常感谢你，Marcin。
John, you're next.
约翰，轮到你了。
John Dehart is a senior research scientist in
约翰·德哈特是一位高级研究科学家，在
the applied research lab at
华盛顿大学圣路易斯分校的应用研究实验室
Washington University in St. Louis.
华盛顿大学圣路易斯分校。
He has been working on network prototype
他一直在研究网络原型。
for research and development and
用于研究和开发
network deployment and management
网络部署和管理
there for the past 32 years.
在过去的32年里。
In addition to managing
除了管理
the global NDN Testbed,
全球NDN测试床，
he also manages the open network lab at
他还管理着开放网络实验室，在
Wash U and has been working as part of
他还在华盛顿大学工作，并且一直是团队的一部分
the 26 labs dot by sheer team
26个实验室由纯粹的团队点缀。
doing tactical NDN network emulation.
进行战术NDN网络仿真。
>> Thank you Davide. I'm going to talk
>> 谢谢Davide。我将要讲述
about the NDN Testbed and how it
关于NDN测试平台以及它如何
ties into our app development
与我们的应用程序开发相结合
and where we should go from here.
和我们接下来应该怎么做。
To start off, I'd just like to
首先，我只想
highlight for people who maybe aren't
为那些可能还不熟悉测试平台是什么的人强调
familiar with the Testbed, what it is.
对于那些可能还不熟悉测试平台是什么的人来说，它是一个我们共享的资源。
It's a shared resource that we
它是我们共享的资源。
run on a global Testbed.
运行在一个全球性的测试平台上。
There's currently 36 nodes
目前有36个节点
in 18 countries on five continents,
在五大洲的18个国家里，
and we haven't quite reached
我们还没有完全到达
Australia and Antarctica yet.
我们还没有完全到达澳大利亚和南极洲。
Each node runs the full suite
每个节点运行完整的套件
of NDN software,
的NDN软件，
the forwarding routing daemon
转发路由守护进程
and other various daemons.
以及其他各种守护进程。
We are always looking for new sites to join.
我们一直在寻找新的网站加入。
You dedicate a machine,
您专门提供一台机器，
either real or virtual to host
托管实体或虚拟的
a node and designate a person to
节点并指定一个人来
be the physical local operator
担任物理本地操作员
in case we need manual
如果我们需要手动干预
intervention at the site.
我们需要在现场进行干预。
We manage the Testbed
我们管理测试平台。
from Wash U in St. Louis.
来自圣路易斯的华盛顿大学。
We use Ansible to go out and
我们使用Ansible去执行外部操作并且
maintain the versions of
维护版本的
everything on all the nodes.
所有节点上的一切。
There's not a lot for
~!@#$%^&*()
the local operator to do.
当地操作员去做。
The test bed is usable by anybody.
试验台可供任何人使用。
We have certificates that are either
我们有的证书要么是基于场所的，要么是访客证书。
site-based or guest certificates.
基于场所的或访客证书。
The links at the bottom are for
底部的链接用于
status page to show the current status of
状态页面用于显示当前状态
the Testbed and for how to find
如何找到Testbed以及如何加入
information if you want to join the Testbed.
如果你想加入Testbed的信息。
Where do we go from here?
我们从这里去哪里？
One big question people ask me is well,
人们经常问我的一个重大问题是，嗯，
who uses that Testbed?
谁使用那个测试平台？
That's a really good question
这是一个非常好的问题。
and I don't have a really good answer.
我没有一个真正好的答案。
I have one superuser
我有一个超级用户。
that is always doing stuff on
总是在做事情的
the Testbed and keeps me on my toes.
总是让我保持警觉。
I'm very thankful that
我非常感激
Jiang Xiao is out there and doing stuff.
江小在外面忙碌着。
I'm curious about other people,
我对其他人很好奇，
who has tried to use it,
谁尝试过使用它，
who has struggled, who's doing what,
谁在努力，谁在做什么，
and how are you using?
你是如何使用的？
What experimentation are you doing?
你在做什么实验？
What's services and apps are you
你在使用什么服务和应用？
trying to run and host on
尝试运行和托管在
the Testbed and then
测试平台上，然后
what would make using
使用测试平台时，然后会使得使用Testbed更加容易和更好。
the Testbed easier and better.
使用Testbed将会更加容易和更好。
Certainly some of the things
当然一些事情
that we're seeing
我们正在看到
in the Slack channel already as we discussed,
在我们讨论过的Slack频道里已经有了，
this is things like tutorials and templates.
这些是像教程和模板这样的东西。
How do I choose names for
我该如何为~!@#$%^&*()选择名字？
my data, from my experiment?
我的数据，来自我的实验？
How do I get my name
我如何得到我的名字？
prefix known on the Testbed?
测试平台上的前缀是怎么知道的？
How is that going to be routed to where I'm,
它将如何被路由到我所在的位置？
where my service or app is running.
它将在哪里运行我的服务或应用程序。
How do I connect my machine to
我如何将我的机器连接到
a specific Testbed node?
to a specific Testbed node?
Things like if I want to run systems
如果我想要运行系统
across the world that connect to
遍布世界各地的连接到
local sites around the world.
遍布世界各地的本地站点。
How do I rent a VM ain country
如何在该国租用虚拟机
x and get it to connect to the Testbed.
并将其连接到测试平台。
Just all those helpful startup hints
只是所有那些有用的创业提示
that people would have
那些人会有
the research themselves.
those people will have the research themselves. If we can find out.
If we can find out
如果我们能找出来
what would make that more
如果我们能找出来什么会让那变得更
useful for people and
对人们更有用
make those hints available.
使这些提示可用。
Lots of other Testbeds
许多其他的测试平台
exist around the world.
存在于世界各地。
Would it be helpful to have
这会有帮助吗？
interoperability
互操作性
with some of those other Testbeds?
与其他一些测试平台有关联吗？
Security, we are always talking about
安全性，我们总是在讨论这个话题。
security for NDN and how important it is.
安全性对于NDN的重要性。
Do we have the infrastructure that you as
我们是否拥有你作为用户现在所需的基础设施？
users need right now
用户现在需要
or is there some piece of that missing?
或者是不是缺少了某部分内容？
Again, tutorials and templates for
再次，教程和模板用于
how do you make use of NDN security.
您如何利用NDN安全性。
Then, as I'm always reminded by
那么，正如我总是被提醒的那样
my previously named superuser,
我以前被称为超级用户，
more regular and frequent updates
更加定期和频繁的更新
of the software on the Testbed are needed to
对测试平台上的软件需要更加定期和频繁的更新，以保持其与正在发生的事情同步。
keep it up-to-date with what's being
保持其与正在发生的事情同步
done in the development side.
完成了开发工作。
That's it for me, Davide.
我就到这里了，Davide。
>> Excellent. Thank you, John.
>> 非常好。谢谢你，John。
We'll move on to Xinyu Ma.
我们将转向马欣宇。
He's a PhD student at
他是一名博士研究生，在
UCLA under the supervision
他是一名博士研究生，在加州大学洛杉矶分校，在Lisa Jiang教授的指导下。
of Professor Lisa Jiang.
他目前的研究重点是江莉莎教授。
He is currently a research focuses
他目前的研究重点是
on antenna applications and libraries.
他目前的研究重点是天线应用和库。
The perfect match for this panel.
这是该面板的完美匹配。
He is the current maintainer of.
他是当前的维护者。
>> [FOREIGN]
~!@#$%^&*()
>> Thank you. I was saying,
>> 谢谢。我是说，
he's the current maintainer of
他是目前的维护者
the Python NDN library
Python NDN库
and the yellow NFT folder.
和黄色的NFT文件夹。
Xinyu, you can go ahead.
鑫宇，你可以开始了。
>> Hi, it's a great chance
>> 嗨，这是一个很好的机会
for me to join this panel.
对我来说，加入这个小组是一个很好的机会。
What I want to share is empowered
我想分享的是被赋予的力量。
developers by a higher level of library.
开发者通过一个更高级别的库获得支持。
Lots of existing libraries
许多现有的库
send a lot of good designs here.
发送许多好的设计到这里。
I think we have such as
我认为我们有诸如此类的。
the SVS and for security we have
我们有SVS，而且为了安全，我们还有
access control and schematized trust
访问控制和模式化信任
and allows for other things
并允许其他事物
such as vertex language,
例如顶点语言，
which is also aquitsing.
~!@#$%^&*()
For storage we have ripple that reward
为了存储，我们有奖励的涟漪。
or at least
或者至少
some more complicated applications.
一些更复杂的应用程序。
It would be great help if
如果能得到帮助，那就太好了。
we can put them together easily.
我们可以轻松地将它们结合起来。
For example, in the HTTP world,
例如，在HTTP世界中，
I still remember that when I
我仍然记得当我
first tried to set up a website,
我第一次尝试建立一个网站时，
a Python library triangle helps
一个名为triangle的Python库帮助
me a lot because it
对我帮助很大，因为它
not only provide a HTTP server
不仅提供了HTTP服务器，
it also helps in database,
它还有助于数据库管理，
which is what I need.
这正是我需要的。
What I want to do is I
我想做的是我
simply should have a common interface for
简单地说，应该有一个共同的接口用于
these different ideas or
这些不同的想法或者
designs so that they can be used
设计，以便它们可以被使用
together in one project by
集成在一个项目中通过
the application developer easily.
应用程序开发者可以轻松地。
It could be a single high level library
它可以是一个高级别的单一库。
that we wanted to be flexible enough.
我们希望它足够灵活。
I would rather call it a
我宁愿称它为一个~!@#$%^&*()
framework so that those ideas or algorithms
框架，以便于那些想法或算法
or new design come up with
或者提出新的设计来适应
different researchers can be fit into
不同的研究者可以被纳入
this framework as a component or as
这个框架作为一个组件或者作为
a module so that
一个模块，以便
the application developer can use
应用程序开发者可以使用
it to call them.
的API来调用它们。我需要说这不是一个强制性的要求。
I need to say this is not a requirement on
我需要说这不是一个强制性的要求。
the libraries because NDN is still evolving.
图书馆们，因为NDN仍在不断发展。
We cannot predict what new library
我们无法预测将会出现什么新图书馆
occurring in the future.
发生在未来。
But rather a plan for
而是一个计划，用于
this library development especially
这个库的开发尤其是
for a present NDN maintaining.
为了目前的NDN维护。
Because I want it to be
因为我希望它能够
flexible and be able to
灵活并且能够
absorb those new ideas
吸收那些新想法
from different people and different team.
来自不同人和不同团队。
Why I believe this thing
为什么我相信这件事
is possible is first,
可能性是首要的。
because there are a set of
因为有一套
similar functionalities
类似的功能
that every application
每个应用程序都需要具备
needs to have,
需要具备，
such as the Sync,
例如同步功能，
and the Trust Management,
以及信任管理，
Access Control and the Repo on those things.
访问控制和这些事情上的代码仓库。
Second is since that data in
第二，由于那些数据在~!@#$%^&*()
the NDN are organized
NDN组织是有组织的
by their semantic names.
按照它们的语义名称。
The programming should also
编程也应该
be organized by names.
按名称来组织。
I think Peter has already showed
我认为彼得已经展示过了
the codes of the senior library.
高级库的代码。
It's quite modular.
它非常模块化。
If the program's structure becomes modular,
如果程序的结构变得模块化，
it is possible for us to provide
我们有可能提供
modular high-level library so
我们有可能提供模块化的高级库，以便
that application can use it in this way.
该应用程序可以以这种方式使用它。
The third is that Jeff's 3S and
同步安全性和
storage, they are orthongonal.
存储，它们是正交的。
For example our application may use
例如，我们的应用程序可能会使用
Pub/Sub with some specific Trust Schema.
发布/订阅模式结合一些特定的信任模式。
It can also choose to use Repo,
它也可以选择使用Repo，
but they are independent.
但它们是独立的。
Whether the application uses Pub/Sub
应用程序是否使用发布/订阅模式
or some other synchronizations does
或者一些其他的同步操作。
not depend on the specific Trust Schema
不依赖于特定的信任模式
or access control tools.
或访问控制工具。
It also does not depends on where
它也不取决于在哪里
and how it wants to deploy the Repo.
以及它想要如何部署Repo。
There are some functions
有一些功能
that are crossing these fields,
跨越这些领域的，
such as the key distribution of the security,
例如安全的密钥分发，
would need synchronization or
可能需要同步或者
Repo to storage that key.
将该密钥存储到仓库中。
But at a very high level,
但在一个非常高的层面上，
there are three aspects kinds of orthogonal.
有三种正交的方面。
The application should be able to choose
应用程序应该能够选择
one spec and then
选择一个规格然后
chose another on another field.
选择另一个领域的其他选项。
If I put all the possible libraries,
如果我放入所有可能的库，
spec from
规格起始于
a manual low-level to the automation.
手动低级别到自动化。
We can get spectrum graph like this.
我们可以这样得到频谱图。
The ndn-cxx and
ndn-cxx 和
the initial existing
初始现有
Python-ndn low level libraries.
Python-ndn 低级别库。
There are a lot of some several projects
有许多个项目
that are using the existing Python-ndn.
正在使用现有的Python-ndn的。
I appreciate that.
我很感激。
I think there is still spaces to
我认为仍有空间可以
improve so that they
改进，以便他们
can write their code easily.
能够轻松编写他们的代码。
There are some specialized libraries
有一些专门的库
such as psynch
例如 psynch
and SVS that's spot sync.
和SVS，那是即时同步。
There are some ready-made software such
有一些现成的软件
as ndn-cert and the python-repo.
有一些现成的软件，比如ndn-cert和python-repo。
My plan for the python- ndn and
我计划对python-ndn和~!@#$%^&*()
new go library I plan to do is out here.
我计划开发的新Go语言库已经在这里了。
We want to provide frameworks
我们想要提供框架
that different designs
可以适应这个框架并且不同的设计
can be fit into this framework and
可以适应这个框架并且
the application developers can
可以适应这个框架并且应用开发者可以
choose what they want to use,
选择他们想要使用的组件，
just as choosing several components
正如选择几个组件
and compose a program.
和编写一个程序。
That's all. Thank you.
这就是全部了。谢谢。
[NOISE]
~!@#$%^&*()
>> All right, excellent.
>> 好的，太棒了。
Thanks. Last but not least,
谢谢。最后但同样重要的是，
Alex Afanasyev, he's
阿列克斯·阿法纳西耶夫，他是
an assistant professor at
阿列克斯·阿法纳西耶夫，他是佛罗里达国际大学的一名助理教授。
FIU, Florida International University.
佛罗里达国际大学。
I will add it general overseer
我将其加入总监督。
coordinator of the vast majority
我担任了绝大多数的协调员。
of NDN software stack.
NDN软件栈。
As I'm sure, many of you know him,
我相信你们很多人都认识他，
he's been in the NDN community working on
他一直在NDN社区工作，致力于
a variety of aspects of
各个方面的
research issues for over a decade.
研究问题超过十年了。
Alex, the floor is yours.
亚历克斯，现在轮到你发言了。
>> Thank you. Let me start
>> 谢谢。让我开始吧
with a few observations,
根据一些观察，
so again depending what
所以再次根据情况
the lessons learned in next steps
在接下来的步骤中吸取的教训
I tried to get
我尝试去获取
maybe little bit low-level step.
也许是稍微低一些的步骤。
First of all, what we have as
首先，我们所拥有的是
a codebase and Beichuan
首先，我们所拥有的是一个代码库和北川 has highlighted a few things.
has highlighted a few things.
北川强调了几点。
I just tried to
我刚刚尝试了一下。
categorize it in different way.
将其以不同的方式分类。
Basically, what we have so far, mainly,
基本上，迄今为止我们主要有的是，
we have a few good exceptions as Peter
基本上，迄今为止我们主要有的是，我们有一些像彼得这样的好例外，
highlighted and I hope the people from Intel,
突出显示了，我希望英特尔的人们，
that already [inaudible]
~!@#$%^&*()
had a darker highlighted.
集中了更多的关注在NDN团队的暗色调突出部分上。
A lot of focus that NDN team
集中了很多关注在NDN团队上。
has been pushing forward
一直在推进
before, and currently,
之前，以及目前，
there is a lot of effort
之前，以及目前，有很多的努力，forward and not just a single one,
forward and not just a single one,
向前发展，而且不止一个，
there is second one, third one,
有第二个，第三个，
fourth one, I don't know,
第四个，我不知道，
I already lost count,
我已经数不清了，
how many forwarders and
多少个货运代理和~!@#$%^&*()
something happening in parallel.
同时发生的事情。
Then there's a lot of effort
那就需要付出很多努力。
that at least in early days,
那至少在早期，
we put in a library.
我们放入了一个图书馆。
I don't think I even listed
我认为我甚至没有列出来
enough those low-level libraries
足够那些底层库
that support really basic primitives,
支持真正基本的原语，
really for the real core stuff.
支持真正核心的东西。
The core staff and the staff
核心员工和员工
that people want to use
人们想要使用
actually is the higher level stuff
实际上是更高层次的东西。
and application focused libraries.
和面向应用程序的库。
Some applications and libraries that are
一些应用程序和库
focusing on the literally
专注于字面意义上的
early adopters and applications.
早期采用者和应用程序。
I'm really hopeful that
我真的很有希望
we actually starting to serious stuff
我们实际上开始认真对待重要的事情了。
[inaudible] has one codebase that
~!@#$%^&*()
has focus in on specific use case.
专注于特定用例。
The whole code development is
整个代码开发是
basically driven by the specific use case.
基本上是由特定的使用案例驱动的。
But this is actually what we need
但这实际上是我们所需要的。
more and I'm hoping
我们能看到这一点在未来。
to see this in the future.
我们将来能看到这个。
Let me highlight
让我来强调一下
a little bit of the question.
一点点问题。
For the high-level point,
对于高层面的观点，
again, this may not be fully correct,
再说一次，这可能不完全正确，
but there's a lot of things that
但有很多事情是这样的，
as NDN team member myself,
作为NDN团队的一员，
specifically, we stuck a little bit
具体来说，我们遇到了一点困难。
on a low-level stuff.
在一些基础层面的事务上。
We keep pre-development forward as fixing
我们在预开发阶段不断向前推进以进行修复。
the forwards even though it's
我们即使在前进的过程中也要继续进行修复，这是一个确实必要的组成部分。
really necessary component.
确实必要的组成部分。
We need more feedback or
我们需要更多的反馈或者
an understanding from the application side.
我们需要从应用端获得更多理解。
Taking those goals from
将那些目标从
the applications and put them in reality.
将那些应用程序放入现实中。
Sometimes there's actually
有时候实际上
conflicting in goals and
目标上的冲突和
this one requires some discussion.
这需要一些讨论。
Real risks requires some understanding
真正的风险需要一些理解。
of what goals we
我们的目标是什么
actually pushing in the forwarders or will
实际上是推进转发器还是会
have separate implementations completely.
完全有独立的实现。
I put the few things here,
我把几样东西放在这里，
is one talking about performance when
他们在谈论表现时候，
suddenly on one hand,
突然一方面，
it's a traditional thinking about
这是一种传统的思维方式
the rowers that they have
他们拥有的划手
to push a lot of data.
推送大量数据。
But there is also
但也有
applications need to push a lot
应用程序需要推送大量
of data inefficient manner.
的数据，方式效率低下。
But then there's the other part
但是还有另一部分
of the spectrum when we're talking about
谈论光谱的另一端时
ad hoc communication
临时沟通
when you're talking about
当你谈论的时候
some like a home IT environments,
一些类似家庭IT环境的地方，
where there's a completely different goal of
在那里有一个完全不同的目标，
having very lightweight communication,
进行非常轻量级的沟通，
which different goal,
进行非常轻量级的沟通，针对不同的目标，
different potential libraries,
不同的潜在库，
different goal for the forward is enter port.
不同的前锋目标是进入港口。
But again, the main problem that we
但再次，我们面临的主要问题是
have is extremely limited development power.
拥有的开发能力极为有限。
I will try to reemphasize
我会尽力再强调
this things couple of times.
我会尽力再强调这件事几次。
We don't have FTEs.
我们没有全职员工。
I saw that one of the questions like why
我看到有一个问题是为什么
something is not in mainstream codebase?
有些东西不在主流代码库中？
We don't have ITs for that.
我们没有专门的IT来处理那个。
We have students that may come and go,
我们有可能来来去去的学生，
that have a different exposure
可能有不同的接触经历。
to development process.
可能有不同的接触经历，但即使是学生，他们也到发展过程。
But even students, they
也在发展过程中。
have mostly focus on research projects
主要集中在研究项目上。
and research project might not necessarily
和研究项目未必一定会
be the codebase related thing.
与代码库相关的事情。
They can develop things,
他们可以开发事物，
there's some patches submitted
有一些补丁被提交了。
for code review and I
将会在代码审查中提及这一点，并且我
will mention about this in second.
将会在稍后提及这一点。
But we also have patches that in
但我们也有补丁，在
code review for years because
多年来的代码审查因为~!@#$%^&*()
nobody is pushing for them.
没有人在推动它们。
But that's the problem of manpower.
但这是人力的问题。
I'll stop on this one. Since up
我会在这里停下来。因为自…
to here that over
~!@#$%^&*()
the years there was tons of codes,
多年来有大量的代码，
tons of ideas that we come up with,
我们想出了许多主意，
we have so many discussions
我们进行了很多讨论。
similar to the discussion we have right now,
类似于我们现在进行的讨论，
effects discussions so far.
迄今为止的效果讨论。
To improve things, to improve visibility,
为了改善状况，提高可见度，
to add new tools.
添加新工具。
But we need people to
但我们需要人来
actually do the stuff and we've made
实际上去做这些事情，我们已经做出了
ourselves and as NDN team
我们自己以及作为NDN团队
wherever the definition for this NDN team is,
无论这个NDN团队的定义何在，
and it varies from time to time.
它随时间而变化。
By ourselves, not
我们自己，不会
going to be able to do that.
我们自己，不会能够做到那一点。
Then I cherry-picked a few things.
然后我挑选了一些东西。
One major pinpoint and
一个主要的难点是~!@#$%^&*()
potentially incorrect perception that we saw,
我们看到的可能不正确的看法是，
we just keep seeing from time to time is,
我们不时地看到的是，
our codebase over this NDN codebase
我们的代码库在这个NDN代码库之上。
is protected,
是受到保护的，
there is a rigid nobody can modify.
有一条规则是僵硬的，没有人可以修改。
This is absolutely not true.
这绝对不是真的。
First of all, our codebases is
首先，我们的代码库是
open-source everybody can see it.
开源的，每个人都可以看到它。
The only thing that we try
我们唯一尝试的事情
to govern is the quality of the code.
就会影响代码的质量。
Because as soon as we take some code in,
因为一旦我们接手了一些代码，
that will become our responsibility
我们就需要负起责任来维护这些代码，
and as a result,
因此，
because we don't have FTEs to do the job,
因为我们没有全职员工来做这项工作，
we have very limited power to the supports.
我们对支持的权力非常有限。
We want to have the initial code good
我们希望初始代码是良好的。
enough to be maintained
足以维护
by very limited power.
通过非常有限的力量。
Basically, the advice
基本上，这些建议
I'm having to address this stuff,
我必须处理这些事情，
if you want the code,
我必须处理这些事情，如果你想要代码，
if you want some tool to be
如果你想要某种工具来
part of the code, please submit it.
如果你想要某种工具来，请给我们提交部分代码。
Please give to us code that
请给我们代码，以便
explain the code to us
请解释代码给我们。
if it's something controversial.
如果这是一些有争议的事情。
Sometimes there are some design decisions
有时候会有一些设计决策
that needs to be discussed,
需要讨论的事情，
and we really have weekly calls
我们确实每周都有电话会议。
that people can join.
任何人都可以加入的电话会议。
announced on public mailing list.
宣布在公共邮件列表上。
You just come to us, explain what you
你只需来找我们，解释你想要做的事情。
want to do we can explain
我们可以解释
what we want to have from the codebase if
我们想要从代码库中获取的是如果
something controversial encodes,
我们想要从代码库中获取的是如果有争议的编码，然后推动代码的更新。
and then push for the code.
然后推动代码的更新。
We may ask about
我们可能会询问
some small changes for the structure,
一些小的结构调整，
changes here and there test.
一些这里那里的小变动测试。
But again, we ourselves don't have FTEs
但我们自己也没有全职员工。
to push [NOISE] your patch.
推送你的补丁。
That's one thing.
这是一件事情。
I'll start the complainant here and then for
我将从这里开始投诉，然后为了
the improvement experience this
提升这方面的体验。
has been already said multiple times.
已经被说过很多次了。
Cathy highlighted a few things, Xinyu,
凯西强调了几点，新宇，
highlighted a few things,
强调了几点，
and some other people also highlighted.
还有一些其他人也强调了这一点。
We really need to have a high-level API soon.
我们真的很快就需要一个高级API了。
Again, the focus we have a lot
我们的焦点很多
was on low-level APIs.
是在低级API上。
But those are not always application stuff,
但那些并不总是应用程序的东西，
or they're technically not
或者它们从技术上来说并不是
supposed to be applications stuff
那些应用程序的构建模块
those building blocks for
那些为了
the application libraries
应用程序库
that should be used.
那应该被使用。
We need more of those and I would say,
我们需要更多这样的东西，我会说，
people, talking about
我们需要更多这样的东西，我会说，人们，讨论关于的例子和用例。
examples and use cases,
例子和用例，
so we need more use cases of those,
所以我们需要更多这些的用例，
where there's a single library,
所以我们需要更多这些的用例，其中有一个库，multiple libraries, I have no clue.
multiple libraries, I have no clue.
多个库，我一点头绪也没有。
This really have to come from
这真的必须来自
the application and tell us
应用程序并告诉我们
what this application really wants to,
是想要通过这个应用程序并告诉我们，
what needs to be exposed.
他们想要通过这个应用程序告诉我们什么需要被曝光。最近我们进行了一些对话
Recently we had some conversations
最近我们进行了一些对话
about whether
关于是否
this intermediate library have to
这个中间库必须要
completely hide the concept of the names,
完全隐藏名称的概念，
concept of the data packets
数据包的概念
inside the library or not.
在图书馆内还是外。
As a question from my perspective,
从我的角度来看，这是一个问题，
I would say immediate
我会说立刻
no, you should not hide.
不，你不应该躲藏。
But this is just my perception because
但这只是我的看法，因为
I have no idea what
我不知道什么~!@#$%^&*()
the actual applications do.
实际应用程序所做的。
Maybe this application or
也许这个应用程序或
application use case have
应用程序使用案例有
nothing to do about it.
对此无能为力。
The second point is especially
第二点尤其
important and this
重要的是这个
really bring back to the periods comment.
确实要回到那个时期的评论。
Things have to be really usable,
事物必须确实可用，
applications should not really
应用程序实际上不应该
care about any connection to NFD.
应用程序实际上不应该关心任何与NFD的连接。
They should not even be
他们甚至不应该
aware of the concept of
他们甚至不应该意识到这个概念，
NFD is just application
NFD仅仅是应用程序。
that requests the data.
请求数据的那个程序。
There is a care to even maybe not even
有一种小心，甚至可能根本不需要小心。
request the data but to publish something,
请求数据但要发布某些内容。
subscribe to something if it's above
如果高于某个值就订阅。
support, synchronize some dataset.
支持，同步一些数据集。
This is the application,
这是应用程序，
whenever we do, we
我们无论何时行动，我们
need to have this working
我们需要让这个运作起来。
and everything is working.
和一切都在运转中。
Similar for the security,
在安全领域也是如此，
not everything in security can be automated,
在安全领域，并不是所有事情都能自动化。
but for everything that
但对于所有能够自动化的事情，我们应该去自动化。
they should be.
能够自动化的事情，应该去自动化。
The problem, again,
问题又来了，
we can talk about this more,
我们可以进一步讨论这个问题，
but we don't have FTEs to do the job.
但我们没有全职员工来做这项工作。
If somebody has idea,
如果有人有想法，
somebody needs to work with
有人需要合作工作
either give this school to us,
将这所学校交给我们，
give the school to the community,
将这所学校交给社区，
We'll have to put it on website,
我们将不得不将其放在网站上，
on our GitHub or the cloner,
我们将不得不将其放在网站上，在我们的GitHub或者克隆者上，并且授予完整的权利去维护它。
give a full rights to maintain it there.
授予完整的权利去维护它。
But again, we have
但我们再次拥有
very limited power of volunteer developers.
志愿开发者的权力非常有限。
This is the last point I
这是我想要表达的最后一点，
was trying to make is,
我试图表达的是，
and I think that I was really
我试图表达的是，我认为我真的
bringing back this several times.
多次提及这个问题。
We need more conversation from
我们需要更多的对话来自~!@#$%^&*()
the use case community
使用案例社区
to us because otherwise,
对我们来说，否则的话，
we're not going to go too much further.
我们不会再走太远了。
For example, the recent conversation
例如，最近的对话
on Slack is talking about,
在Slack上正在讨论的内容，
give this quick guide
给出这个快速指南
to this, quick guide to that.
给出这个快速指南, 到那个快速指南。
I don't know what
我不知道什么
the applications are to
应用程序是为了
give the specific use case.
提供具体的使用案例。
I can imagine, but that would be
我可以想象，但那将会是
my perspective of not
我的不同观点
exactly working with applications.
精确地处理应用程序工作。
Hopefully there's more conversation
希望会有更多的对话。
from mailing list,
来自邮件列表，
public NDN, Slack,
公共NDN、Slack，
or direct email that
或直接发送电子邮件，让我们知道您需要什么样的
tell us what kind of
告诉我们您需要什么样的
use cases we need to work on,
我们需要着手处理的用例，
like what examples we should give.
像我们应该给出哪些例子。
Again, this is
再次，这是
the last point that maybe it's
最后一点或许是
for the more internal discussion.
为了更深入的内部讨论。
We still have some resources, for example,
我们仍然有一些资源，例如，
Davide is a great resource for development.
Davide是开发的一个很好的资源。
[LAUGHTER]
~!@#$%^&*()
Given all these limited resources,
鉴于所有这些有限的资源，
we still have to figure out how to use it.
我们仍然需要弄清楚如何使用它。
We need to potentially
我们可能需要
change some of
改变一些
the priorities in development,
改变一些发展中的优先事项，
but hopefully, reduce
但希望能够减少
fracture of the codebase.
代码库的分裂。
This is a little bit to
这有一点儿
what Peter was saying before,
彼得之前说的话，
so I'll stop. I've talked too much.
所以我会停下来。我说得太多了。
>> Yes, you certainly did.
是的，你确实说得很多。
[LAUGHTER] That's fine,
那很好。
lots of great points.
很多很好的观点。
Thanks, Alex.
谢谢，亚历克斯。
We're done with the initial remarks
我们已经完成了初步的评论。
and we can get
我们可以得到
more into the discussion phase of this panel.
我们可以得到更深入的讨论阶段的这个小组。
As we saw lots of
我们看到很多来自不同背景的
different backgrounds and
不同背景的
a wide spectrum of opinions.
各种不同的意见。
But I was also glad to see
但我也很高兴看到
that there seems to be a lot
但我也很高兴看到似乎有很多
of several points,
在几个要点上，
where at least our panelists agree,
在至少我们的小组成员同意的地方，
there seems to be
在至少我们的小组成员同意的地方，似乎有一些共识在建立中
some consensus about building
在建立中的一些共识
high-level APIs and easier to use libraries.
高级API和更易用的库。
The point is, how do we get there?
关键是，我们怎么到达那里？
There's really over 100 comments
已经有超过100条评论了。
in the Slack channel.
在Slack频道中。
Some of that is already chatter
有些已经是闲聊了。
and back and forth between the panelists.
和在小组成员之间来回讨论。
Do any of you feel strongly
你们中有谁有强烈的感受吗？
about what other panelists said?
关于其他小组成员所说的内容？
Is there something you strongly agree
你是否非常同意其他小组成员所说的内容？
with or strongly disagree with?
是否强烈同意还是强烈不同意？
Just as a provocation.
仅仅作为一种挑衅。
>> I don't know whether it's
我不知道这是否是
an agreement or disagreement.
一个协议或不同意见。
I think Marcin was talking about there is
我认为Marcin在谈论的是存在着
a lack of automation tools
自动化工具的缺乏
with Ansible and other stuff.
与Ansible及其他相关工具一起。
I couldn't really understand what exactly is
我真的不太明白究竟是什么
lacking because this is
缺乏，因为这是~!@#$%^&*()
just deployment things,
只是部署的事情，
and then, there are
还有，
software packages that [OVERLAPPING]
软件包那些[重叠]
>> The one is deployment.
>> 那个是部署。
Sorry, you're right.
对不起，你说得对。
The one is in deployment.
这个正在部署中。
How you are deploying application.
你是如何部署应用程序的。
But to be honest, to be deployer
但说实话，要成为部署者
through business and so on,
通过商业等方式，
you need to provide those integrations.
你需要提供那些集成服务。
For example, if you have your application,
例如，如果你有你自己的应用程序，
let's see you showcase the feasibility.
让我们看看你展示可行性的情况。
Somehow you need to integrate it in the flow.
你需要以某种方式将其融入到流程中。
Otherwise, your application
否则，你的申请
will be taken even into account.
否则，你的申请将甚至不会被考虑在内。
At this moment to have
在此时拥有
success in application and even the support,
在应用中的成功甚至支持，
the NDN network,
NDN网络，
you need to provide
您需要提供
nearly the whole building box.
几乎整个建筑盒子。
The question is, as we know that we
问题是，正如我们所知道的，我们
have researched one at a time,
我们已经逐一研究过了，
and there was a great comment
我们已经逐一研究过了，这是一个很好的评论，from the Kaitlin Nichols,
from the Kaitlin Nichols,
来自Kaitlin Nichols，
who should take care of all this stuff that's
需要谁来负责所有这些事情呢？
definitely needs to be done by
肯定需要由
businesses and to someone
企业和某人
who is supporting those use cases.
支持这些用例的是谁。
But the question is,
但问题是，
if there is no much of your application,
如果你的应用程序不是很多，
that can be fully taken by
那可以被完全承担由
the businesses and the users
企业和用户
and spread word who should take it?
并传播这个消息，谁应该接手呢？
Who should do that job
谁应该做那项工作？
to show the full feasibility
展示全部的可行性
and the end-to-end integration of NDN?
和NDN的端到端集成？
As I said, I think it's
正如我所说，我认为这是~!@#$%^&*()
a great time because we
正如我所说，我认为这是一个很好的时刻，因为我们~!@#$%^&*(), are at the start of the edge.
are at the start of the edge.
我们正处于边缘的开始。
We see that lots of
我们看到很多
new libraries to support the Edge deployment.
新的库来支持边缘部署。
I think that there is a big opportunity
我认为这里有一个很大的机会
for NDN, but the question is,
但问题是，
lack of time and resources
时间和资源的不足
are lagging the time
落后于时代
for a shine for NDN in many cases.
在许多情况下，为NDN增添光彩。
>> I think that goes
我认为那是正确的。
along with a point that has
伴随着一个已经被Alex在他的幻灯片中，在他的演讲中提到的观点。
I have personally witnessed many times,
我亲眼见证了很多次，
there seems to be different
似乎有不同
and sometimes competing directions.
和有时是相互竞争的方向。
There's a researcher that wants
有一位研究者想要
to do research with NDN which may
进行NDN研究，这可能会
have different needs
有不同的需求
from the application developers
来自应用程序开发者
that are in the industry
那些在行业中的
that just want a package
那些只想要一个包裹的
and get it up and
并将其提起来
running as quickly as possible,
尽可能快地跑步，
as effortlessly
尽可能轻松地，
they don't want to waste
他们不想浪费
their time with the plumbing.
他们不想在管道工作上浪费时间。
There might be someone
可能会有人
that cares about performance,
关心性能的，
they had to move a vast quantities
他们不得不搬运大量~!@#$%^&*()
of data that they care about.
他们关心的大量数据。
Others may care about Edge environments
其他人可能关心边缘计算环境。
where performance is not maybe
性能可能并非是主要关注点。
the primary concern or mobility.
性能可能并非是主要关注点，而是移动性。Alex指出了这一点，
Alex pointed this out,
亚历克斯指出了这一点，
towards the end of his talk he said,
在他的演讲快结束时他说，
given the low resources, put a constraint,
在资源有限的情况下，施加一个限制，
the resources that we have,
我们拥有的资源，
we should pick a direction
我们应该选择一个方向。
and focus on that one.
并专注于那一个。
Is this a good approach?
这是一个好方法吗？
What do others think?
别人怎么看呢？
>> Alternatively, we just need
>> 或者，我们只需要
get the money.
拿到钱。
[LAUGHTER]
~!@#$%^&*()
>> Alternatively, if
>> 或者，如果
you've got more resources,
你拥有了更多资源，
you can pick more directions, certainly, yes.
你可以选择更多的方向，当然可以。
>> Can I add?
>> 当然可以增加。
>> Hello. Can you hear me? To me
>> 你好。你能听到我吗？对我来说
I think the use case
我认为用例
that is better to focus on is
更应该专注于的是
the hands-on local NFD node setup.
手头上的本地NFD节点设置。
Maybe it will address a little bit of
也许它会稍微解决一些
Alex's question on what
亚历克斯对什么的问题
the quick start guide should be.
快速入门指南应该是。
There are many aspects, and I agree.
有很多方面，我同意。
But when you land on the page of IPFS,
但当你登陆IPFS的页面时，
you have maybe that many commands
你可能有那么多命令。
you have to run to start fetching a file.
你得运行命令来开始获取文件。
If you have two machines locally,
如果你本地有两台机器，
you can do it on two machines and
从每台机器上获取文件。
I think the quick start guide,
我认为快速入门指南，
what I would like to see is a quick start for
我希望看到的是一个快速入门指南，
five or 10 machines or
五台或十台机器或者
whatever the number is
无论数字是多少
that I just run the commands.
我只是运行命令。
Then these machines, they run NDN,
那么这些机器，它们运行NDN，
then I can run
那么我就可以运行
even the simplest application
即使是最简单的应用程序
like Indian pink is
像印度粉红色一样是
fine as an example or fetch
像一个例子一样好或者去取
your file ndn was it ket chunks, food chunks.
~!@#$%^&*()
But I don't have to worry
但我不必担心
about built-in n of D configuring it,
关于内置的D配置它，
configuring routes, configuring faces,
配置路由，配置界面，
because this is what I've been through.
因为这是我经历过的。
This is my experience actually,
这其实是我的亲身经历。
applications that were built.
构建的应用程序。
It has at least five computers
它至少有五台电脑。
and I have to run around them,
我得围着它们跑来跑去。
I have to note every machines IP address,
我得记下每台机器的IP地址，
and then I have to think like
然后我得想办法
what the prefixes
前缀
should be and do it all myself.
应该自己去做所有的事情。
Then it's just an experience that is not
那么这只是一种不是
pleasing for people who
对人们来说是令人愉悦的
are not invested in a project,
对于那些并不想投入某个项目的人来说，
for people who just want to try it.
对于那些只是想尝试一下的人来说。
They will stop when
他们将会在什么时候停止。
they learned that they need to
他们了解到他们需要
remember five different IP addresses
记住五个不同的IP地址
and register routes they will not do it.
并注册路由，他们不会这么做。
To me, that's the end
对我来说，那就是结束。
of the quick start guide.
快速入门指南的。
>> I think you're
>> 我认为你是
tackling exactly the same problem.
解决完全相同的问题。
For example, this [inaudible]
For example, this [无法听清]
results in many cases
导致了许多情况
to [inaudible] or any other libraries
导致了许多情况，对[听不清]或任何其他库 that are using those Cloud-native deployment.
that are using those Cloud-native deployment.
这些使用了那些云原生部署的。
Even if you're deploying
即使你正在部署
your Kubernetes or any other software,
你的 Kubernetes 或者任何其他软件，
you have the external library 3D instance.
你有外部库的3D实例。
That is a great experience.
这是一次很棒的经历。
Someone in a five-minute can just have,
有人只需五分钟就可以，
with the five clicks, deploy the system.
仅需五次点击，即可部署系统。
The great example of the success
伟大的成功典范
is Kubernetes mini, is K-SVD,
~!@#$%^&*()
meaning when someone with
意思是当某人带着
two clicks can do it on
两次点击就能完成。
the Windows or Linux machine and can also
Windows或Linux机器上也可以
have the multiple host deployment
可以进行多主机部署
can just tell,
~!@#$%^&*()
give a list of IP addresses
提供一个IP地址列表
where it needs to be deployed.
它需要被部署的地方。
It will take care of
它将会处理
the security layer and all of those layer.
安全层以及所有那些层。
This, what is
~!@#$%^&*()
called the fully seamless experience
称为完全无缝体验
for the developers or
对于开发者或
even the future operators which would
即使是将来的操作员也会
try the system and they're having.
尝试系统并且他们正在使用。
I think that the key is the car
我认为关键是汽车。
at this moment because as you were saying,
在这一刻，因为正如你所说，
any of this is a key component.
这一切都是关键组成部分。
You should have this easy way to deploying it
你应该有这种简单的部署方式。
and it showcases across
并且它在各个方面展示了
the developers and also research community.
开发者以及研究社区。
Because everyone from this,
因为每个人都来自这里，
our environment will have
我们的环境将会有
some gains as developers,
我们的环境将会有一些收获，作为开发者，
operators, everyone who wants to try it out.
我们的环境将会有一些收获，作为开发者，操作员，以及任何想尝试的人。>> There seems to be also an issue
>> There seems to be also an issue
>> 似乎还存在一个问题
of scale where maybe
规模上可能会
your regular app developer
普通的应用程序开发者
doesn't want to deal with Kubernetes at all,
根本就不想要处理Kubernetes，
that it doesn't need to deploy
它不需要部署
a whole network just
一个完整的网络只是
to test their applications.
来测试他们的应用程序。
I think that's why maybe that
我认为也许那就是原因
was one of the original goals for building
是建造的最初目标之一
this Indian task that Joel maintains.
这项由Joel维护的印度任务。
But it seems that people are not
但看起来人们并不是
using it or maybe
正在使用它或者也许
there aren't that many
没有那么多
applications in the first place.
首先的应用程序。
But it's certainly not easy.
但这当然不容易。
One of the inputs as a community
作为一个社区的其中一个输入项
also is why aren't people using it,
也是为什么人们不使用它的原因，
how we can improve that experience.
我们如何能够改善那种体验。
Sidestepping the whole,
绕开整个问题，
I have to deploy a network part.
我需要部署一个网络部分。
If you can use a test bit
如果你能使用一个测试位
for some quick testing,
进行一些快速测试，
then you can sidestep
然后你可以绕过
the whole deployment part,
整个部署部分，
why is that not working,
为什么这不起作用？
maybe Peter has experience with
也许彼得在这方面有经验
that and as an as an application developer.
那个，作为一个应用程序开发者。
>> [inaudible] you had wanted to comment.
~!@#$%^&*()
>> I have a quick comment about the test,
>> 我对测试有一个简短的评论，
asking the question why
询问原因为何？
people are not using it?
人们没有使用它？
Well, with the use case
好吧，关于使用场景
that I explained earlier,
我之前解释过的，
when I set up locally and then
当我在本地设置然后
I see how simple it is,
我明白了，这有多简单，
the next thing I would be
我接下来要做的事情会是
thinking for my app is moving to the Cloud,
我接下来要做的事情会是为我的应用程序思考迁移到云端，
moving to the testbed or
迁移到测试环境或者
moving to EC2 instances or whatever.
迁移到EC2实例或其他类似的服务。
I think like at the very beginning,
我认为就像最开始一样，
it's hard, there's a lot of friction.
它很难，存在很多摩擦。
There's a lot of friction of
There's a lot of friction of ~!@#$%^&*()
setting it up locally.
在本地设置它。
People are not even thinking about moving to
人们甚至还没有考虑搬到
the testbed. That's how I see.
人们甚至还没有考虑搬到试验台上。这就是我的看法。Cathy,
>> I see what you mean. Cathy,
我明白你的意思了，Cathy，
you said you wanted to comment?
你说你想评论吗？
>> I just thought the new comment
>> 我只是想说新的评论
[OVERLAPPING].
~!@#$%^&*()
>> Hold on a second.
稍等一下。
>> I was just going to say that some
我只是想说有些
of maybe my perspective is
的确，我的观点可能有些不同，因为我非常专注于
different because I'm very focused on
不同，因为我非常专注于
particular types of applications that test
特定类型的应用程序用于测试
better something you spoke to me
更好的是你对我说过的事情
because I'm thinking about
因为我在思考
things that work at the edge and don't really
在边缘运作但实际上并不需要在互联网风格中转发，
need forwarding in the Internet style,
实际上需要以互联网的方式转发，
in fact, forwarding is
实际上，转发是
a anti goal because
一个反目标，因为
you don't want data to go everywhere.
你不希望数据到处泄露。
I don't really want to be putting
我真的不想放置
down the things that are being done in order
放下正在有序进行的事情
to build a wider network,
为了建立更广泛的网络，
but I do think that there are always
但我确实认为总是有一些途径
some common things that
可以穿越我们所有人都做的一些共同事情。
cross the things that we all do.
穿越我们所有人都做的事情。
But then that also gets me back to,
但那也让我回到了，
I want the freedom to do
我想要自由去做……
these things that I do that gives
我所做的这些事情给予
the architecture that I don't
我不喜欢的建筑结构
want to be dragging along what to me
是我不想拖着走的东西
is a boat anchor of stuff that in order
是一堆拖累的东西，需要按顺序来处理
to do this more Internet style communication.
进行这种更具互联网风格的交流。
I don't know, maybe this comes
我不知道，也许这来自于
from a more advanced development
来自于更高级的发展
researchy side that I'm back to the idea
研究性的一面让我回到了这个想法
of being welcoming to people,
对人们表示欢迎，
doing different applications,
进行不同的应用程序操作，
especially if you're going to be application
尤其是如果你要进行应用程序操作，
oriented instead of,
面向而不是，
how do we move this from
我们如何将这个从
here to here, oriented?
从这里到这里，定向了吗？
>> [inaudible] almost exactly like this.
[无法听清] 几乎完全是这样的。
Not all application have
[无法听清] 几乎完全是这样的。Not all applications have any sense to you, the tester.
any sense to you, the tester.
对你来说，作为测试者，这没有任何意义。
A calm environment,
一个平静的环境，
[inaudible] environment applications.
~!@#$%^&*()
I don't know even how to plug in the
我甚至不知道怎么插上这个
>> Certainly, yes. Good point.
>> 当然，是的。说得好。
>> Davide, you have
>> 大卫，你有
a raised hand in the audience.
观众中有人举手。
>> Yeah. I saw it. I was just going in order.
>> 嗯，我看到了。我只是按顺序来的。
>> Okay.
>> 好的。
>> Yeah. What is it?
>> 嗯。什么事？
Yes. [inaudible] Sampson.
是的。[听不清]桑普森。
>> Yeah. Hi guys. Thanks very much.
是的。大家好。非常感谢。
>> You have a question.
>> 你有一个问题。
>> I do. Can you hear me?
>> 我能。你能听见我吗？
>> Yeah. Go ahead.
>> 好的。继续说。
>> Okay. This might come as somewhat
>> 好的。这可能有点
a surprise and it's come as a bit
这确实有点让人惊讶，它出乎我们的意料。
of a surprise to us, I have to admit,.
确实让我们有点惊讶，我必须承认。
But we've been working on something for
但我们一直在研究一个项目已经有
ten years that looks like it's
十年来，它看起来似乎是这样的，
about to come to market with
即将推向市场
a fairly significant budget to build
建立一个相当可观的预算
a global network
一个全球网络
using a lot of the principles of
使用许多原则
Indian and conduct centric networking.
印度和以行为为中心的网络。
There's a lot of the history
有很多历史
which I won't go into,
我不会详述，
but in essence, we are potentially going
但实质上，我们可能将要
to be quite a large user
可能会成为相当大的用户
of the Indian libraries.
的印度图书馆。
We absolutely love the Indian libraries
我们绝对喜欢印度的图书馆。
because we're building from the ground up.
因为我们是从零开始建设的。
The libraries are incredibly useful to us.
图书馆对我们来说非常有用。
The testbed is incredibly useful.
测试床非常有用。
Everything you're doing is incredibly
Everything you're doing is incredibly ~!@#$%^&*()
useful except as I've
有用，除了我之前在一些评论中提到的那样，
made in some of the comments,
在一些评论中提到的，
we could just do with a bit more of
我们只需要再多一点儿
user documentation to help
用户文档以帮助
us find our way around.
我们找到我们的路。
Look, I fully admit we're in a typical user,
看，我完全承认我们是一个典型的用户，
but I think just
但我认为只是
as what the guys we're working with,
作为我们正在合作的那些人，
we're looking for, we
我们正在寻找的，我们
may be what you guys are looking for,
可能是你们正在寻找的，
which is a fairly serious application
这是一个相当严肃的应用。
of the technology.
的技术。
Fingers crossed, we'll know
希望我们能在接下来的几周内知道
in the next couple of weeks.
希望我们能在接下来的几周内知道。
We've got a statement of work
我们有一份工作说明书。
with a potential customer.
与潜在客户。
It's to build a team of 20 people
组建一个20人的团队。
for a year to build this.
我们需要一年时间来建造这个。
It's a pretty serious project and
这是一个相当严肃的项目，
it will be a global network.
它将会是一个全球性网络。
I guess that's my two cents worth.
我猜这就是我微不足道的意见。
That really for us
这对我们来说真的很重要。
what you're doing is fantastic.
你正在做的事情太棒了。
It's absolutely fantastic.
这真是太棒了。
It fits perfectly with what we're doing.
它与我们正在做的事情完美契合。
In fact some of
实际上有些
the earlier speakers have
实际上有些早先的演讲者已经
talked about what's missing.
实际上有些早先的演讲者已经谈到了缺失的部分。Build schedule has all of that in it.
Build schedule has all of that in it.
建设进度表已经包含了所有这些内容。
We've got DevOps and particularly
我们已经采用了DevOps，特别是
distributed optimization
分布式优化
of routing and forwarding,
的路由和转发，
content-based routing and forwarding.
基于内容的路由和转发。
We're working with a guy
我们正在和一个人合作。
called Hemi Locker from
我们正在和一个叫Hemi Locker的人合作。
Bell Labs who may or may not be online,
我们正在和一个叫Hemi Locker的人合作，他可能在线也可能不在线的贝尔实验室的一员。
who is one of
我们正在和一个叫Hemi Locker的人合作，他可能在线也可能不在线的贝尔实验室的一员，who is one of the world leaders in network optimization.
the world leaders in network optimization.
网络优化领域的世界领导者。
I'm going a bit round in circles.
我有点绕圈子。
>> [OVERLAPPING] That's great to know.
>> 那真是太好了。
Thank you. That's good to know.
谢谢。知道这个很好。
I'm glad and surprised
我既高兴又惊讶。
that someone is doing this even
尽管有人甚至在做这些
though all this pain coming from
尽管有这些痛苦来源于~!@#$%^&*()
our libraries has been
我们的图书馆已经……(Translation is incomplete due to insufficient input for a complete sentence)
apparent from our speaker panelists today.
显然从我们今天的发言嘉宾那里可以看出来。
It's refreshing to hear this experience.
这种经历听起来很让人耳目一新。
>> Well, I have to admit we
好吧，我不得不承认我们还没有深入研究这些库，
haven't dived into the libraries yet,
不得不承认我们还没有深入研究这些库，
so I may have
所以我可能会有
a different opinion once we do that.
所以我可能会有一种不同的看法，一旦我们那样做。
>> I was going over some of
>> 我正在仔细研究一些
the numerous comments in the Slack channel.
Slack 频道中众多的评论。
There was a comment, I
我认为这是Cathy说的。
She's concerned about the notion of
她对这个概念感到担忧。
one library that Peter mentioned.
彼得提到的一个图书馆。
This ties back to this direction problem.
这与方向问题有关。
He says maybe she wants to say
他说也许她想要说
directly on the mike.
直接对着麦克风。
There are some issues with
存在一些问题
the drivers that are
存在一些问题的驱动程序
out there and it
在外面，它似乎可以更有效率。
seems like they could be more efficient.
似乎它们可以更高效。
I would hate to stifle
我不愿意扼杀
improvement and innovation.
改进和创新。
We are risking that
我们正在冒险
by choosing one direction
选择一个方向
or focusing on one library.
或者专注于一个库。
>> That was a problem that I've found in
>> 那是我发现的一个问题，在
particular that might happen to other people.
那可能也会发生在其他人身上的一些特别的事情。
to the application [inaudible].
~!@#$%^&*()
When I wanted to put
当我想要放进去时
different signing into the packet,
将文件签名放入包裹时，
everything is so tangled
一切都如此纠缠不清。
together that it was
如此紧密地联系在一起。
really difficult to do that.
真的很难做到这一点。
Which is why I've
这就是为什么我已经~!@#$%^&*()
had to pull it out and I did put it
不得不把它拿出来，我确实放进去了
in toolkit that I'd put out in
不得不把它拿出来，我确实放进去了，在工具箱里，以防其他人需要
case anybody else wanted
万一有其他人需要
to experiment with that.
进行实验。
I think we should be making it
我认为我们应该使其
possible for people to
尽可能让人们能够
try new things and encourage it.
尽可能让人们能够尝试新事物并鼓励这种行为。
I'm a little worried about
我有点担心
if we go towards libraries,
如果我们走向图书馆，
especially libraries that are very
特别是那些非常
entangled and difficult to get to
纠缠不清，难以解决
one module and work
一个模块和工作
on it if your research interests
如果这是你的研究兴趣所在
are in your packet signing or something.
在你的包裹签名或类似的事情上。
I mean, you shouldn't have
我的意思是，你本不应该
to learn all this other stuff.
你本不应该学习所有这些其他的东西。
I'm just concerned about
我只是担心
the idea of saying that we should only
我们应该只有这个想法是说
have one library since
我们应该只有一个图书馆因为
the libraries that are out there
那些外面的图书馆
seem entangled to me.
似乎让我感到纠缠不清。
>> Any other comment on this point?
>> 对这一点还有其他评论吗？
>> I can quick comment.
>> 我可以快速评论一下。
I was looking at it from
我是从这个角度来看的
a perspective maybe not
一个或许不同的视角
more of research or app development,
更多地关注研究或应用开发，
but more like a
但更像是一个
general purpose half developer.
通用型半开发者。
The one go to
你会首选的
library that you would start with,
你会首选的图书馆，
that is a high level library
这是一个高级图书馆。
where you don't have to worry about
在这里你不必担心
slicing your data into segments and
将你的数据分割成段落并且
then assembling it again on the other end.
然后在另一端重新组装起来。
The other thing I wanted to
我还想要提到的另一件事是
mention in my slides and forgot
提到在我的幻灯片中忘记了
actually the CNL library
实际上是CNL图书馆
that was actually proceeding this goal of
这实际上是为了实现这个目标而进行的
being high level name
这是一个高层次的名称。
centered or data-centered library.
以数据为中心的库。
Right now this repo I
~!@#$%^&*()
think it's obsolete or something.
我认为它已经过时了或者有什么问题。
So it's not supported.
所以它没有得到支持。
No one's maintaining it.
没有人在维护它。
I think this is it.
我认为就是这样。
A good example that we should reflect on.
我们应该反思的一个好例子。
Why is it abandoned?
为什么它被遗弃了？
I think it never had enough users.
我认为它从来没有足够的用户。
Then the resources ended
然后资源就耗尽了。
and then everything stopped.
然后一切都停止了。
But maybe we don't
但或许我们不需要
have to invent new libraries,
不必去发明新的库，
maybe we already have
也许我们已经有了
old pieces that line somewhere in the corners
旧的碎片散落在角落里
that we need to graph and
我们需要绘制图表并且
just start bringing life back to it.
开始让它重新焕发生机。
[LAUGHTER].
[笑声]。
>> The lack of resources again.
>> 资源再次短缺。
This seems to be a fundamental tension
这似乎是一种基本的紧张关系
between building simple things
之间构建简单的东西
that people can play with or work on,
可以让人们玩耍或者工作的，
swap components or replace components.
更换零件或替换零件。
By components I mean sub
通过组件，我的意思是子组件。
pieces of the library.
图书馆的一部分。
More like the signing that Cathy mentioned.
更像是凯西提到的签名。
Tension between this and
这和张力之间
having ready to use old batteries included
包括随时可用的旧电池
package for application developers
适用于应用程序开发者的软件包
that don't want to deal with that.
不想处理那个。
I'm not sure if
我不确定是否
I see a solution to this tension.
我看到了缓解这种紧张关系的解决办法。
Maybe there doesn't have to be one.
也许不一定非得有一个解决办法。
Isha had a comment. Isha.
Isha有一个评论。Isha。
>> Yeah, this was some time ago,
是的，这是很久以前的事了。
but let me just do it quick.
但是让我快速地做一下。
I think that [inaudible] mentioned about
我认为那个[听不清]提到了~!@#$%^&*()
our former networking does
我们以前的网络做...
not meet the testbed.
没有达到测试环境的要求。
It depends.
这取决于具体情况。
home network fully controlled
家庭网络完全受控
by the end users.
由最终用户控制。
We're now excluding clause.
我们现在排除条款。
The Cloud resources are always
云资源总是~!@#$%^&*()
useful as enjoys economy of scale.
有用的是因为它享受规模经济的好处。
The fundamental thing is
基础的事情是
really who is in control
真的，谁在掌控一切？
at mounted in the disconnected from outside.
在安装时与外界断开连接。
That was something happened
那是发生过的事情。
long time ago when that gives some effort.
很久以前，当那需要付出一些努力。
But now see's talk
但现在，看看她们的谈话吧。
about what a library or multiple libraries.
大约是关于一个图书馆或多个图书馆的事情。
There are probably,
大概是，
there are different ways
有不同的方法
to look at that problem.
来看待那个问题。
Peter mentioned why he wished to see that on
彼得提到了他为什么想要看到那个在
the one hand level library that
彼得提到了他为什么想要看到那个在一方面层次的库，它实际上具有所有的组件，以便
actually has all the components so that
实际上具有所有的组件，以便
[inaudible] doesn't have to
~!@#$%^&*()
go shopping people on
去购物的人在……
a piece of art one place,
一件艺术品一个地方，
given that the pieces from different places.
考虑到这些艺术品来自不同的地方。
But in parallel, I think Katie is right
但同时，我认为凯蒂是对的。
that at this time in research,
在这个时候的研究中，
we should let a 100 flowers bloom.
我们应该让百花齐放。
[inaudible] has his own way
[无法听清]有他自己的方式。
of building the libraries.
他想要建立图书馆。
He wants to get
他想要得到
the Python library and on the go.
他想要得到Python库并在外出时使用。
Also, being flexible enough and being able
to utilize resources already 同样，足够灵活并能够利用已有资源。
to utilize resources already
利用已有资源
built for other libraries.
利用为其他图书馆建造的资源。
I think that sounds
我认为那听起来
to me is a good direction to go.
我认为那听起来对我来说是一个好的方向。
As a matter of fact, am not
事实上，我不是
making advertisement for his library,
为他的图书馆做广告，
for the Python the
为了Python，这...
rather late for the very quickly got
为了非常快速地得到，已经相当晚了
the pick that by some recent
为了非常快速地得到，已经相当晚了，the pick that by some recent, applications like a professor.
applications like a professor
应用程序就像一个教授。
[inaudible] there
~!@#$%^&*()
is an augmented reality app,
是一款增强现实应用程序，
where is the Python library,
位于哪里？
then the newly started the project?
那么新开始的项目呢？
I think consistent we're
我认为我们是一致的
going to talk tomorrow,
明天要谈的内容，
probably the
大概是
hydraulic distributed storage system.
液压分布式存储系统。
It's also being built on
它也正在建设之中
top of the Python library.
Python库的顶部。
I think it should
我认为它应该
attract to one of the libraries
吸引到其中一个图书馆去
>> Thank you.
>> 谢谢。
>> Thanks, Lixia. We're running out of time.
>> 谢谢，丽霞。我们的时间不多了。
I wanted to see if there's one last round of
我想看看是否还有最后一轮
comments one second each.
每条评论一秒钟。
[OVERLAPPING].
~!@#$%^&*()
>> Yeah, let me.
好的，让我来。
>> I'm feeling the tension between
我感受到了紧张的气氛。
this single library idea,
这个单一图书馆的想法，
and we needto some startup thing and
我们需要做一些创业方面的事情。
putting together full toolkit
组装完整的工具包
for people who develop applications.
对于开发应用程序的人来说。
I think we're at the point where
我认为我们已经到了这样一个地步，在这里
the application development that we need
我们需要的应用程序开发
to take a step back and
退后一步并且
start building the stepping
开始建造踏步
stones for people.
为人们铺设石头。
Having a simple library that someone
可以使用来做那个第一次应用。
Then if we look at the sync libraries,
那么如果我们来看看同步库，
they have been maturing
他们一直在成熟。
over the past couple of years.
在过去的几年里。
I think we're really focusing now
我认为我们现在真的很专注。
on a vector sync that people could use.
一旦他们开始使用向量同步。
Once they get on
一旦他们开始使用向量同步，那第一块垫脚石在哪里
that first stepping stone where
就在那里。
they can do a simple application,
他们可以做一个简单的申请，
then they can start
然后他们可以开始
using something like sync,
使用类似同步的功能，
and then they're going to realize, hey,
然后他们会意识到，嘿，
I need to incorporate security.
我需要加强安全性。
Then pulling this security
然后提高这个安全性。
library that they could use,
可以使用的库，
and as people use
以及人们使用
those stepping stones we are
我们所使用的那些垫脚石，我们将不得不对它们进行完善，以...
going to have to refine them to
我们将不得不对它们进行完善，以
make them better and more usable.
我们将不得不对它们进行完善，以使它们更好、更实用。
But don't try and
但不要试图
go for the full gamut right away,
但不要试图一次尝试所有的可能性，
but make sure we have
但要确保我们有
solid stepping stones for
坚实的垫脚石给
people to start down that path.
人们开始沿着那条路前进。
>> That's an excellent point. Thanks, John.
>> 那是一个很好的观点。谢谢，约翰。
>> I just want to say that
>> 我只想说
the toolkit that I have,
我拥有的工具箱，
this isn't necessarily going
这不一定会发生
to work for everyone.
为了让每个人都受益。
But one of the things is,
但其中一点是，
there is a API into the trust schema,
存在一个进入信任模式的API，
controlled transport that is
受控传输是指
meant to be somewhat like MQTT.
旨在某种程度上类似于MQTT。
You can write something
你可以写一些东西。
on it and you publish and subscribe,
在上面你可以发布和订阅，
and you don't need
而且你不需要
to know all of this other stuff.
你不需要知道所有这些其他的事情。
Unfortunately, you have to write now,
很遗憾，你现在必须写。
get NFT up and running,
搭建并运行NFT平台，
and all of that but we're
正在努力简化这一切，但我们正在
working on making that easier.
正在努力让这变得更简单。
I'm not saying this is the end,
我并不是说这就是结束，
that everyone should do this,
但这是每个人都应该做的事情，
but this is something that
everyone should do, and after that, anyone else can take a look.
anyone else can take a look
其他人可以看一看。
at then if they're,
那么如果他们在的话，
see what is useful to them or not.
看看哪些对他们有用，哪些没有。
We've tried to make it modular and
我们已经尽力使它模块化并且
it all concepts, the C++,
它涵盖了所有概念，C++，
and the libraries are all header files,
这些库都是头文件，
so they're more like modern library style.
所以它们更像是现代库的风格。
That's all I have to say.
我就说到这里。
>> Talking about sync
>> 谈论同步
libraries that Peter mentioned,
彼得提到的那些图书馆，
it seems that's fine,
好像没问题，
just gets abandoned because
因为就被遗弃了
there's less of manpower.
人手不足。
That library if my memory is correct,
那个图书馆如果我没记错的话，
it's developed by one
那是由一个人开发的。
person and that person is
那个人是
done so that leverages get abandoned.
完成了，这样杠杆就会被放弃。
I don't think there is
我认为没有
a design issue with that library
那个库的一个设计问题
and my Python at end is inspired by that,
而我的Python最终也是受到那个的启发。
and you are seeing that a lot.
而你经常会看到那个。
I think I will go
我想我会去
the same direction or
相同的方向或者
at least very similar direction to present,
至少与目前的方向非常相似，
future development of Python Indian.
Python在印度的未来发展。
>> That is a good result for
>> 这是一个好结果，对于
library if it's inspired you for more work.
图书馆如果它激励了你去做更多的工作。
Just in case I am resurrecting this library,
如果我正在复兴这个图书馆的话，
I updated it to Indian end.
我把它更新到了印度的末端。
What I wanted to add in the end is that
我最后想要补充的是
maybe to soften my depressing comments,
或许为了缓和我那些令人沮丧的评论，
it's not all that bad actually.
其实并不是那么糟糕。
I think the thing that I tried to build,
我尝试构建的东西，
I tried to document and
我尝试记录并且
put out as easy to use things,
发布成易于使用的东西，
and I learned a lot from,
和我从中学到了很多，
I would call it somewhat
我会说它有点儿
failed Indian RPC library.
印度RPC库失败了。
No one really built
没有人真正构建过
an app except me using this library.
除了我使用这个库之外，没有人真的构建过一个应用程序。
But, when I
除了我
build new libraries and components,
构建新的库和组件，
just trying to,
努力去尽可能地让它对用户友好。
make it as user-friendly as possible.
尽可能地使其对用户友好。
Put it in that package managers
将其放入那个包管理器中。
like broil APT,
像APT一样进行软件包管理，
so people can install
所以人们可以安装
it without building from source.
因此人们可以安装它而无需从源代码构建。
Just have a few examples
只需几个例子
on how to use it right away,
就能立刻知道如何使用它，
I think if people who create
我认为，如果创造它们的人能立刻知道如何使用它，他们自己的组件会尝试去做到这一点，
their own components will try to do that,
他们自己的组件会尝试去做到这一点，
that's that's good enough.
这已经足够好了。
[OVERLAPPING]
~!@#$%^&*()
>> Do I have to pick? Marcin go first.
>> 我必须要选吗？Marcin你先来。
>> What I heard, just like lots
>> 我听到的，就像很多钱涌入了那个图书馆
of money comes about the one library
涌入那个图书馆的钱
and this unified view
和这个统一的观点
of some of the things I rewrite.
我们需要对我重写的一些内容有所了解。
We need to have
我们需要有
just a share compound applications that are
我们需要有共享复合应用程序，这些程序能够完全支持并且能够
fully supported and be
完全支持并且能够
able to show the full visibility.
能够完全显示可见性。
That's really count on board and
这确实取决于董事会的决定。
helps and refresh their focus
帮助他们并且重新集中他们的注意力。
to start out with MGM.
从美高梅开始。
I think that's a really helpful.
我认为那真的很有帮助。
Also fall what we heard is really a loss
我们听说的也是真的亏损。
of the needs for this type of
满足这种类型需求的
API being to help
API 被用来帮助
the couple authors to
API 被用来帮助 the couple authors to build an application logs.
build an application logs.
构建应用程序日志。
I think it not
我认为不是这样的。
right we don't need them one language.
我们不需要只有一种语言。
We need the many languages,
我们需要多种语言。
even though libraries, one
即使图书馆，一个
supported by him in many ways,
他在许多方面给予支持，
if you want to run something called using
如果你想运行所谓的使用
Golan and you no longer need the Golan,
高兰，你不再需要高兰，
we should use the Golan
我们应该使用高兰
as one of the language,
作为一种语言，
and it's the same with the C++.
和C++也是一样的。
We should have the full freedom of
我们应该拥有完全的自由来
choosing your developer and their own.
选择你的开发者和他们自己。
>> Alex, do you want to conclude?
>> Alex，你想做个总结吗？
>> Absolutely, two points.
>> 当然，两点。
We need to multiple levers
我们需要多个杠杆。
for many languages is
对多种语言来说是
just a question of
仅仅是一个问题
what a heck are we going to
我们到底要怎么办
support all those stuff.
支持所有这些东西。
That's the only problem.
这就是唯一的问题。
I don't have any other issues.
我没有其他问题。
I wish we had put
我希望我们已经放置了
every possible language in the world.
我们已经放置了每一种可能的语言在世界上。
Whoever likes incredible modern,
谁喜欢令人难以置信的现代，
I don't know what to do
我不知道该怎么办。
fancier than the rest.
比其他的都要高级。
>> Just use as the fanciest
>> 只需使用最高级的
right now. It's the greatest.
现在。它是最伟大的。
>> Maybe something for lists.
也许适合列出清单。
But that would [inaudible] coupled.
但那会[听不清]耦合。
But another one that I
但另一个我
just want to make a tiny comment,
只想稍微评论一下，
not really concluding
关于约翰所说的内容，并没有真正得出结论。
regarding what John said.
关于约翰所说的内容。
I think this stepping stone is
我认为这个踏脚石是
a traditional way of going
我认为这个踏脚石是一种传统的前进方式，在地面上从头开始应用开发。
in ground-up application development
在地面上从头开始应用开发
with tempo securities at the end.
在最后加上节奏证券。
Somehow we don't know
有时候我们不知道
how I don't have a solution.
有时候我不知道怎么解决。
But maybe Cathy's way
但或许Cathy的方式
of thinking about the implementation,
的实施方式思考，
where you start with the application that is
在应用程序开始的地方，
secured and then you add
加固之后，然后你添加
some communication elements maybe.
一些沟通元素也许会有。
[LAUGHTER] Again,
[笑声] 再来一次，
that's my just a weird point about this.
这就是我觉得这个问题有点奇怪的地方。
>> Thank you. With this
>> 谢谢。有了这个
we're seven minutes over time.
我们已经超时七分钟了。
I think we could go on for hours
我觉得我们可以继续讨论好几个小时。
with a very productive,
与非常有成效的，
interesting discussion.
有趣的讨论。
But unfortunately, we have to conclude,
但不幸的是，我们必须结束讨论。
we have to stop here.
我们必须在这里停止。
I'd like to thank again all the panelists.
我要再次感谢所有的小组成员。
I believe we have a lunch break or whatever,
我相信我们有一个午餐休息时间或类似的安排。
depending on our time zone.
取决于我们所在的时区。
We're resuming at 1:30 for second session.
我们将在1:30恢复第二场会议。
I'll see you back at
我们将在1:30恢复第二场会议。1:30 Eastern. Thank you again.
1:30 Eastern. Thank you again.
我们将在东部时间1:30恢复第二场会议。再次感谢。